<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<dataset>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for telling my colleague to &quot;suck it up or quit&quot; when she complains about unpaid work?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="telling the truth" intention="conforming to norms" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>This doesn't happen often, but once in a while when the company gets busy we may need to help out outside our working hours, attendance compulsory. We are not paid for that period and instead compensated by additional annual leaves. Trust me, when it happens it sucks, we all hate it, we curse under our breath but we do what must be done because that is how the company works, and yeah, in times like this especially nobody wants to lose their job.//There is this young staff(early 20s) that doesn't know how to deal with it though. Ever since she knew that 2 weeks from now she is required to work on a Saturday, she has been complaining. As her partner on the role, I become her outlet and I have been hearing her telling me that we should protest and complain to HR, demand to be paid, demand to have the right to refuse etc.//I kept telling her that there is no way around it, HR won't care(they aren't like those HR of justice and power I've heard so much on reddit, not sure if it's the norm), the superiors won't care(they are working that day too), and we are powerless against them, so we should just grit our teeth and work through it since it doesn't happen often. The staff wouldn't let it off and kept complaining and complaining for the past whole week.//She was urging me to help her to protest together again earlier, I turned her down again because I don't want any trouble and just want to do my job and keep my job. I told her that she could go file a complaint herself but she got angry and told me that I should be helping her, everyone should be working together and protest against free labor. It was at this point that she wasn't even doing her job properly and led me to cover up for her lack of work. I got impatient and told her that &quot;Nobody is going to protest, and nobody cares if you do. You can either suck it up and do your job or quit. &quot;//I get it, I lost my temper for a bit and should have handled it better. However I think that she also needs to know that not everything in real life works the way it should be and sometimes, we just have to bear with it and not taking it out on others. She is young, but she should have the maturity to know that much. I've apologized to her already but she has not been talking to me. Not that I mind, finally some peace but AITA for saying what I said?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA- Am I the asshole for making a coworker upset when I corrected her that we were just “coworkers” and not “friends”?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="nan" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Kind of a weird post but it just happened so I want to know if I’m the asshole. I just left a job that I had for over 2 years. During that time I had come to like many of my coworkers but I didn’t consider them to be friends as, in my opinion, friends are people who you hang out with and are able to text/ call out of the blue. I understand that my opinion of “friend” may not be the universal definition of friend but I have used this definition in my life and I consider people who fit the above description friends. All others are coworkers and colleagues. So if I don’t hang out or text you about non work related things then I am not your friend.//On my last day at work, a former coworker of my mine kept saying they would miss me and kept referring to me as their friend. I reminded them that while I enjoy their company at work, I don’t consider us to be friends. They were confused as they thought we were. I reminded them that every time I asked them to hang out outside of work, they would say no and would give reasons that ranged from understandable to one’s that were, well obvious that they didn’t want to hang out with me. I soon realized that maybe we weren’t going to be friends and that I had a coworker that was a colleague who I could talk to during work hours. I let them know that I only consider people my friend if I hang out with them outside of work. They tried to laugh it off as if I was not being serious. I told them I was serious and that I would consider them a coworker. They got upset and said that friends come in all different varieties and that we were friends because we had conversations at work. I politely informed them, that while they might see that as a friendship, I did not. I saw us as coworkers.//My coworker got quiet and didn’t continue the conversation. They then called me an asshole for making them upset. I was confused as it was a cordial conversation. Am I the asshole for making my coworker upset that I didn’t consider them a friend?//Edit: I forget that sometimes I don’t write out what I’m thinking. Just for clarification, the reason I said I did not see us a friends was because this person would go out and hang out with other people from the office and would tell me about it during lunch. Whenever I would ask to hang out it would always be a polite, no thank you. And that is fine. That would make us just coworkers. Maybe I am being petty. Coincidentally, I also have friends that I hang out with outside of work from this job.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for refusing to apologize to my coworker?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="M" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Throwaway account because I know he uses reddit.//So, about 2 months ago, I got a new coworker. He sat in a desk a few spaces away from me. He would come over to chat sometimes, I didn’t mind it. He was young and in his 20’s and just seemed really curious about starting a new office job.//I didn’t mind the small talk at first. It would just be like a quick “Hey, how was your day, what are you doing for lunch?” Yada yada yada. But the more we talked the longer the conversations progressed.//Im the type of person who can’t focus when somebody is talking to me. So I usually try to drown him out. But whenever I look away or look at my computer for too long, he goes “Heyy are you even listening to me” or something along those lines. Oh yeah, I’d totally love to listen so intently about the new thing your cat did this week.//This started happening about a month ago and it’s just gotten worse. The conversations have gone up to about 30 minutes. I always try to be like “Hey, I’m kind of busy right now can we finish this conversation later?” But he says he just has one more thing to tell me and continues to ramble again and again.//Last week, he came over to my desk again. I was annoyed, but I dealt with it, whatever.//About 5 minutes into the conversation, I was working on this document and closed it out, and immediately realized I forgot to save it. I reopened it hoping that it somehow saved but nope, 1 hour of work gone.//I became very visibly annoyed. He noticed this and said “Hey what’s wrong?” I told him what had happened and all he said was “Oh.. sorrry.” Then proceeded to start to tell me about a time that happened to him.//At this point I was fed up, so I cut him off and said “Geez, you never shut up do you?”//He went silent and his face immediately dropped. He looked at me with a sad expression and walked off. I didn’t think too much of it at the time but when I got home I started feeling a little bad.//When I got to work the next day though, he came up to my desk again and told me to apologize. I asked him what for, and he told me what I said was incredibly rude and he was just trying to make friends. I told him sometimes he can be a bit overbearing and that I had just lost an hours worth of work so I was very heated in the moment. He still told me that was rude and I need to apologize. I refused to apologize so he walked away.//We haven’t spoken for a week now. I don’t think I should apologize because he clearly doesn’t understand boundaries, but then again I do feel a bit bad.//I asked my boyfriend about it too and he said I was definitely being an AH. But I don’t think so.//So, am I the AH?//So, am I the AH?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for asking my coworker if she deliberately wears clothes that show her cleavage?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="conforming to norms" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>We (the company) had a new employee &quot;Christina&quot; working in our section and she's a nice lady in her late 30s. She's married with kids. We had several conversations before. We work close by and one time she was sitting and moved to the side and her already showing cleavage got clearer. The office got awkward and the guys there looked down. it was obviously something minor but it kept happening. I had a couple of our male coworkers complain to me about Christina's cleavage (I'm more of a tomboy woman so the men feel comfortable enough around me) they were saying that having to be forced to encouter a similar situation to the one I mention makes them uncomfortable. I couldn't help but notice that all the clothes, tops specifically that Christina wears are designed to show cleavage. I brought it up to her the next day and casually pointed out how her cleavage was showing. She said nothing, just noded at me. I went ahead and asked if she deliberately wears clothes that show her cleavage. She looked offended and asked if there was a problem. I flatout said that it felt weird to me if this was the case and that it was kind of weird also that a married woman is okay with her cleavage showing at a professional workplace with male co workers around. She got upset and asked how it was any of my business what she chooses to wear. respectfully, I told her she could wear whatever she want but some employees just don't feel comfortable having been exposed to this kind of stuff at work. She told me that it was none of my business and that those who have an issue with her clothes should stop being cowerds hiding behind me and come talk to her face to face. We had an argument and some of my female coworkers agreed with me though said that I could've phrased this better. Christina started avoiding half of us which seemed unprofessional because part of our job is to interact but she chooses to stay away. I tried talking to her and another argument started with her saying she'd take this to the administrators if &quot;I keep it up&quot; but I was really just trying to talk things out.//AITA for what I said to her?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for throwing away my coworkers sweater" op_gender="nan" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>My coworker 55m has a sweater that he wears everyday at work and leaves in the office overnight. He NEVER takes it home to wash and over the last month it has developed a distinct smell.//At first I tried to make innocuous comments to him (&quot;Do you smell something musty?&quot; etc )//But he didn't catch on so last week I said to him &quot;Hey that sweater is starting to give off a stench, could you take it home and wash it?&quot; He replied &quot;Nah that's not my sweater&quot; and walked away which effectively ended the conversation.//After he left one night I went to his desk and smelled the sweater and confirmed that nasty stank and it was so putrid up close (I have no idea how he lives like this)//So I took the sweater on my way out and threw it in a dumpster out back.//The next day he was looking around for it and asking everyone if they had seen it. I just shrugged and said &quot;Nah haven't seen it today&quot; (which was technically not a lie)//I feel kinda bad but I can't live like that. We work in a 7 person office with no HR and our boss is not effective at dealing with issues do I felt like this was my only option. AITA?//CLARIFICATION: when he said &quot;that's not my sweater&quot; he was referring to the stink not being his sweater. The sweater was in fact his (he's a bit of an oddball, but I can't imagine even he would wear a random stinky sweater that he didn't own)</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for refusing to donate $1 to my employer?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="nan" experience="nan" relationship="inferior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="damage to reputation" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I teach at a private school in an insanely wealthy area. One year of student tuition costs more than my car. More than 90% of our students’ families are multi-millionaires. However the school is technically a non-profit and relies heavily on donations to balance the budget each year.//Part of the school’s strategy to get more donors is to have every employee donate some money to the school. Then they tell the donors “Our employees care soooo much about the school that 100% of them donate to our general fund.”//This means that they put a lot of pressure on us to donate any amount of money, but they make it clear the amount does not matter. Even $1 is enough for them to advertise 100% participation. It is heavily implied that if anyone doesn’t participate it hurts the whole fundraising campaign.//The whole thing rubs me the wrong way. Either I get guilted into donating significant money to my employer… or I donate $1 and become complicit in the 100% participation deception. I know it’s not technically a lie if I donate $1 but it still feels deceitful to me. Either way I feel like an asshole.//Last year I stuck to my guns and refused to donate. In a faculty meeting they announced “Thanks to everyone that donated we were able to get nearly 100% participation.” Immediately the room erupted into “Who didn’t donate?!”. Which I think just highlights the problem of the system. But it could also just be an indicator that I need to stop being the stick in the mud and hand over a damn dollar.//So am I the asshole?//TL;DR - Employer wants all employees to donate at least $1 to be able to market “how much we care about this place.” I refuse.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for chatting in the office and having a loud voice?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="violating professional boundaries" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="No" perspective="No">
		<content>I’ve been having some trouble at my current job, it’s my first office job since being in retail and studying at uni, it’s a big adjustment in a completely new sector. I feel the culture there is super old fashioned, it’s governed by all old white men and some of the rules are ridiculous. Things like women aren’t allowed to wear shorts but men are? Anyway, I was pulled up by my manager for not being good enough at the job and slacking by going on my phone and chatting too much. I thought fair enough I will take that; so I’ve cracked on with my work and I’m getting everything done on time and to a good standard.//Today I was getting on with my work while talking to a colleague having light chat to pass the time, I wasn’t turned facing this colleague, I was typing away and sound was coming out of my mouth..so one of the managers tells us to quieten down as he couldn’t hear his teams meeting. We did exactly that and stayed quiet, later on I get a call from my manager and she says she’s received an email from him saying how frustrated he is with hearing my voice and me talking (even though I’m doing my work). I’m naturally a chatty bubbly person and I just have the urge to vocalise my feelings and say things. My manager also went onto say how the big boss is also sick of hearing me complain and say I don’t understand things and that I’m confused…she pulled me up on speaking about subjects such as “lunch” and “coffee” and deemed them inappropriate while my male colleagues talk about football for hours and they haven’t had such comments said to them.//I feel this is an attack on me as a person and my core being. She said the others don’t get pulled up because my voice is the loudest” I can’t help how I sound..I’ve struggled with it my whole life. I have good intentions, I want to do my work and have a good relationship with my colleagues. Does this make me the AH?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for Including my coworker in Secret Santa when she clearly does not want to be in it?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>My work has 7 female employees including the 2 bosses. Needless to say we are all very close and interact with each other on the daily, even hang out outside of work.//My, f26, coworker, f45, had a bad experience with last years secret Santa. We had it split into 3 weeks for the last three weeks of December. Week 1- trinket, week 2 - trinket, week 3- final gift, exchange and staff dinner.//Her first two gifts came the following week, which ruined her experience of looking for her gift and waiting for it to appear in the designated week, and she also felt that her final gift was below budget and not thought out (a wallet). As everyone was having their own experience, admittedly we didn’t notice how bad her’s was.//This year October we selected the names for secret Santa. This is when she told everyone about her experience and how terrible it was, mentioning it multiple times to different people and saying that she does not want to be involved this year.//In charge, I still put her name in the generator, me and one of the bosses hoping to persuade her as we made a rule in the generator her and her past Santa would not get each other. It did not work.//Instead I asked her to show me who she got, and decided to get the gifts for both her and my original person, without telling her Santa that she was not participating. This was done so that she could still receive a gift , without having to put in the effort.//Late November, after people started buying gifts she made a comment stating that she does not only does she not want to be a part of it but if she gets a gift she will leave it there at work.//There is NO WAY that she would not receive a gift. Either I would have 3 secret Santas, or the bosses would still get her a gift.//It would be terrible for the next 3 weeks for all to be excited about a surprise gift knowing she’s not involved or receiving. Her past Santa would feel guilty and not be able to enjoy the festivities. We would feel awkward brandishing gifts with her right there. The final brunch would be weird after we closed work to exchange the last gifts.//I understand her stance, but I feel that we should at least be able to make it up to her- stress free on her end, so that everyone can enjoy the festivities .//My thoughts have even gone as far as thinking she is selfish because she knows how small work is and how it will impact the holiday season. Just accepting the gifts graciously is fine because we are only doing it to make her feel included, and to make up for last year! We aren’t forcing her to buy anyone a gift.//As her gym partner , and someone who hangs out with her outside of work- I could never receive a gift and be excited to talk to her about it knowing she can’t enjoy it as well- and she’d have 2 bad christmases at work. But maybe I’m being selfish?//Am I the asshole for ignoring her wishes and including her anyway?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for lying to my boss about my religion?" op_gender="M" target_gender="M" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="no" action="lying or misrepresenting information" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I 20m got a job at an upscale restaurant at my city owned by a father and his son managing. Now I have a lot of respect for this man but his son is an entitled little prick who was constantly making derogatory gay jokes to and about this one waiter as well as horribly misogynistic comments. He constantly micromanages and refuses to accept any fault.//I hate when people sing happy birthday at a restaurant because I know anxiety is very common and no one really enjoys doing or receiving it so I always ask when people say they're celebrating a birthday if they'd like someone to sing. Sometimes they say yes other times they say no.//My boss completely ignored me when I said a young girl didn't want anyone to sing and tried to force me to do it anyway. I refused and when he asked why I lied and said I was a jehovahs witness because I knew they couldn't legally force me to go against &quot;my&quot; religion (I'm an atheist but that wouldn't have been good enough). He then got someone else to do it and when they were done I apologised privately to the girl, saying that I did what I could. She had this pained look and said it was fine and that she appreciated the effort.//After that I was off the hook for any birthday or Christmas celebrations (much to the annoyance of my boss). Everything was fine until one of my coworkers that I thought was a good friend saw me drinking at another bar and ratted me out. I was then fired for lying about my religion even though I pointed out that religious people don't always abide by their religion (Jews don't always eat kosher, Christians sometimes have premarital sex, etc.)//Everyone there including the friends I had made called me filthy names and the bosses son blacklisted me. I still maintain it was none of their business and stand on the principle I mentioned above.//Am I the asshole?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA-For ignoring my boss and blocking his number on my vacation?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="higher" relationship="inferior" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="yes" action="ignoring or neglecting duties or people" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>My boyfriend (29 m) and I (26 f) are currently long-distance. We take turns visiting each other. He came to see me after almost two months of not seeing each other. We finally were to make plans. I requested to have five days off which was approved from my job. I’ve worked there for six years. I’m a security guard at a department store.//It was after my shift, and I was heading out quickly. I had to pick my bf up from the airport. I clocked out, and while I was saying bye to everyone. My new boss of 2 weeks stopped me, and he asked if I could cover a shift. Since one of my co-workers called in sick. We’re short-staffed, and he needs me to stay for a couple hours more. I had a 10-hour shift. I was exhausted.//I responded no. I’m sorry, but I’m unable to do that, and I can’t stay late. I have covered shifts before in the past. I don’t mind, but I had somewhere to be. I mentioned I was picking up someone at the airport. He told me they could take an Uber. My boyfriend wouldn’t be happy with me if I did to him. Also he has no key to my apartment.//No one else wanted to stay, and I was the third person he asked to that said no. I said sorry, I can’t just tonight, another time.//He called me a lousy worker, and I’m not a team player. I said, guess I’m not a team player and I walked passed him. I called out. I’ll see him in five days. While driving to the airport, I kept getting calls and texts from him; it got so bad that I had to pull over to turn off my phone. My boss wanted me to come back to work.//I had to turn on my phone, so my boyfriend could contact me. My phone was flooded with text messages. Ding after ding I think I got close to 15 texts. I blocked his number.//I was so happy to see my bf. I was getting emails from my boss constantly when I was supposed to be my time off. I didn’t respond to and I rarely take vacation. One, he was asking me stuff that I didn’t know the answer to. Second, even if I did, I’m not telling him. I don’t know; I was starting to get petty.//I still had fun with my boyfriend. When I went to work, my boss called me into his office. He blew up at me for being unprofessional, and he’s still new to this job. I should’ve helped or at least replied to the emails. I responded other people could’ve helped him. It’s not my responsibility when it’s my vacation time. I got my first write-up ever.//Is this something I’m missing? Did I do something inherently wrong here? I’m actually considering to report him. He is still new to his job. Am I the asshole?//Edit: I’m Canadian. I live in BC.//Update: I just sent an email to my HR with all the emails texts call logs. And any other evidence I have. My job isn’t like on call.So I don’t understand why he was bothering me he is my age roughly. On a happier note me and my boyfriend are planning to move in together//Edit: I’m a security guard at a departmental store. I like my job. HR Is setting a meeting up for tomorrow with me and my boss. My boss Tried asking me out in his first week of working But I told him down (nicely).//Edit: Thank you for everyone’s support. When I posted this I thought I was being a little dramatic. I’m glad I’m not the crazy one. I decided that I’m gonna look for a new job. I still wanna do security work but I’m just gonna move on. Don’t worry I’m still going to complain about my boss And report him.//Final update. My boss was fired.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for berating an employee in front of all her coworkers and making her cry?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="lower" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="seeking fairness or justice" impact="damage to reputation" good_standing="Yes" perspective="Yes">
		<content>OK title sounds bad but hear me out. So for context I (26f) have been working at a corporate job for about a year, it's great, pays really well and I get along with pretty much everyone. However, there's this manager at work, let's call her Leanne (~40f) and most of us don't get on with her at all, as she's always humiliating people by talking down to us. For example my coworker has a lisp and last week when she asked him how far along he was with a project he said it would still take another while, she basically blew up at him but half of the time when she was screaming at him, she was putting on a fake lisp to mock him. She'll always leave a pile of work onto other people because she needs to leave work to collect her kids from school when the father doesn't show up to collect them when it's his turn. Another thing is she always expects us to stay on later than expected and coming in earlier, but we don't get paid for this time.//That's just a few examples because if I listed all of the things she's, it would go over the word limit.//So today I got told I'm being promoted to a much higher position within the company, I'm excited about it as it pays better and will give me a lot more responsibility. The thing is this position basically will make Leanne my subordinate. So I was telling a few coworkers about the promotion, we were just standing in the break room laughing and chatting and she came in.//She started giving out about us not working, saying things like 'oh I get it, you guys must think you're on vacation just because its a nice day out do you?', at one point she turned to my Mexican coworker and said 'you shouldn't add to the stereotypes' and eventually said 'if you people don't get your butts back to your office right now, I'm going to report it to higher management'//The more she talked the angrier I got and when she finally finished berating us I stood silently for a second and then just said something like 'I'll consider this being you reporting it to higher management, as that's currently my position in [company]'. One of my coworkers snorted and Leanne looked furious.//Then I just told her that me and my coworkers were okay to be in the break room, as it was literally our break time, that it was pretty rich to tell us we couldn't take a coffee break when she herself would leave work regularly to pick up her kids because her ex husband couldn't be bothered. I said that she wasn't to speak to any of us like that anymore or I'd have her written up within the minute.//She stood there for like a whole minute it felt like and started tearing up, then she left without a word. I felt horrible afterwards because i humiliated her in front of people shes managing and made her cry, my coworkers are saying she had it coming but one of them thinks I went too far bringing her kids into it. So AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for saying that I would report my colleague for foul language instead of helping her reporting another person for harassment?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="healthcare" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="retaliation" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>I(23F) had been transferred to a department since Feb with 12 men and only 2 women, me and another senior lady &quot;Kat&quot;. In this department we were more like a big family than just colleagues as we are essential workers(make a guess, not telling) and it was everyone's company that kept us going through the busy nights, especially in times like this.//I was the youngest and newest then, so the guys were very helpful and patient with me. One big guy &quot;Tom&quot; was very physically affectionate and he loves to pat, hug, mock wrestle, squeeze cheeks and lightly slap the younger staffs on the back, including me.//I don't mind Tom treating me like the guys, in fact I think that he just a sweet cuddly bear, and sometimes I squeeze him back too. I never felt uncomfortable among the guys and I know they are all decent people.//About a week ago we had one additional staff, another lady &quot;Amy&quot;(21). As you may have guessed from the title now, Amy got mad when Tom attempted to hug her and when Tom realized that, he quickly apologized and mentioned that he thought she wouldn't mind because I didn't. Amy said something like this.//&quot;Just because dirty sluts love getting touched by guys doesn't mean all women do!&quot;//Obviously I took it as an insult, I haven't done anything to Amy and she straight up said that in front of all the guys. I was tired and I didn't want to start a fight so I pretended I didn't hear it, but Amy kept yelling at Tom as he apologized profusely with a few other guys trying to calm her down.//Later on Amy approached me and told me that she needed my help to report Tom for harassment, and she got Kat backing her up. Still tired and in a bad mood, I replied sarcastically &quot;Yeah, I shall report too, you for your foul language, and the guys will back me up because they heard what you called me.&quot;//Amy got really upset at me because she assumed that all women should stand up to the men, but she's got nerve wanting my help reporting my friend after insulting me out of nowhere. Kat told us to sort it out before leaving because she feels that she is too busy for drama and Amy got angrier because now she has nobody to back her up, and she blames it on me.//Just to be clear, I am not reporting anybody, too tired for that shit. Tom and Amy can sort it out between themselves and I am not going to bother with either of them. Go on.//Info: After reading some comments there are some common misconceptions that I would like to clarify.//No, Tom does not touch butts and breasts, if he does forget about Amy don't you think I would have long did something about it?? Common sense people. Tom is like a brother or uncle to us younger staffs.//We do work professionally but because our job requires us to work away from home, lots of communication and moving around, especially when we work overnights it us common for us to talk casually and joke/mess around to some extent so that we can stay alert. This us more than common office like environment so despite being tiring we a have god relationships with each other.//Kat is one of the seniors in the department, so naturally Tom does not mess with her, but she knows about Tom and as as I have no complaints she doesn't care what he does. When Amy got offended, Kat is also one of the first to reach her side and told Tom off. I suppose Amy then convinced her to help her to report Tom for harassment but since she changed her mind, Amy is alone in this now.//I don't mean to justify Tom's actions. He made a wrong assumption and that's on him. However, since Amy had be as nice as to imply me for being a &quot;dirty slut&quot; a, I see no reason helping her. Had she also apologized to me we could have worked it out with Tom in a civilized manner without resorting to complaining to the upper management. But now, I don't want anything to do with the case between Amy and Tom, they are able adults and pretty sure they could work it out themselves.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for deliberately running up mileage on a company car?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="M" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="labor" condition="yes" action="stealing or misusing company resources" intention="following rules" impact="financial consequences" good_standing="Yes" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I have been working for Barry for 4 years. When I first came to work as his apprentice I was the only person he employed. He now has a construction company with 19 employees.//Recently after having repeated issues with new young hires he introduced a &quot;no phones on the work site&quot; policy. I assumed this didn't apply to me as it seemed to be in relation to a couple of incidents with new hires and also as site manager I needed my phone on me to contact Barry if there was a problem on site as he would usually be at his house drafting plans or in meetings while the rest of us were on the work sites that were between 10-40mins drive away and outside of driving there was no other way to contact him.//About a week after the policy came in I called him in relation to an issue we had found(water main in a different place to where the plans showed and right where we were supposed to be driving piles) and he basically tore a strip off me in front of everyone.//That was 4 weeks ago and I haven't had my phone on me whilst on the clock since. Instead I drive the company car to his house every time there's a problem. Obviously this makes projects go much slower and has been chewing through more gas than usual but he didn't notice until this week when he was checking last months books and noticed that the average gas consumption had almost doubled and several jobs that would've normally been completed hadn't.//He called me beside himself and I pointed out that I had no other option as he didn't want me using my phone, he told me to use common sense and I said that I had been and I'd gotten a new asshole torn for it. He hung up and hasn't mentioned it but after discussing it with my wife I'm starting to feel guilty. Did I go too far?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for embarrassing a guy with a &quot;shy bladder&quot; at work." op_gender="M" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="helping others" impact="damage to reputation" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>The men's room where I work has a wall of urinals and four stalls.//There is one guy who apparently cannot use a urinal.//However he must have a firehose and a sore back because he never lifts the seat when he urinates and he pisses all over the toilet.//Like not just a little sprinkle either. He gets it on the seat, the tank, the floor. I'm surprised he doesn't hit the walls.//I'm overweight myself and I have trouble using the urinals sometimes. So I tend to use a stall. But I sit to take care of number one as well as number two.//Anyways I put up a sign in the stalls that I remembered from my grandparents' home.//&quot;If you sprinkle when you tinkle be a sweetie and wipe the seatie&quot;.//He took this as a personal attack. He ripped them all down and came into the break room and was yelling about having a shy bladder and that he doesn't have to use a urinal and a bunch of other stuff.//The thing is none of us knew for sure it was him that did it.//I didn't target him or anything. I talked privately to him and told him that the signs were for everyone and that he just outed himself.//He called me an asshole for making him embarrass himself and that he was going to HR.//I was just trying to politely ask everyone to clean up after themselves.//AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for telling my manager that my coworker was high when she got injured at work?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I work in a cafe. We serve bagels and coffee in the mornings, and we are usually slammed from 6am to 9am. My coworker and I are the only people at the counter, so she slices and toasts people’s bagels, and I would get their coffees, and take their orders. We normally have a pretty good system. Recently our baker has been making the bagels very soft, and they have been getting stuck in the slicer. We have a pusher to deal with this, but most of my coworkers and even my manager, just pushes more bagels through (and it pushes the stuck ones out).//On Wednesday we had an accident with the slicer. My coworker reached too far in and sliced the top of her finger. It was barely holding on. She had to go to the hospital, and the slicer had to be taken apart and disinfected. All of my coworkers were buzzing about the accident. I hung out at the counter with the manager, who was pissed about having to take the slicer apart, and having to report the injury.//I have seen several of my coworkers smoke joints together in the morning before coming into work. I think that this is extremely unprofessional, but I’ve never made any comments about it. I keep to myself. This time felt different, so I let my manager know that she and several other workers smoke before shifts. It could be why she got hurt. My manager noted this, and I guess she indicated it in the injury report.//Turns out that coworker may not be eligible for workman’s comp because of this, and may have to foot the bill for the reattachment of her finger. I don’t know if someone overheard me talking about it, but someone told my coworker that I “snitched” on her. I overheard a other coworker call me a snitch and an asshole. People are definitely giving me the cold shoulder. I feel isolated. I feel as if I was just being honest, but I’m unsure. Am I an asshole in this situation Reddit?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for telling my new co worker it was misleading of him to be wearing his wedding band when he's a widower?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Hi. A couple of weeks ago we had a new employee hired at the company. he's a good guy and a widower named &quot;James&quot; (36) and to my knowledge his late wife passed away 8 months ago. Me (f32) and the other coworkers got along well with him. However I noticed that he is still wearing his wedding band on his finger. It kind of confused me a bit and I couldn't help but bring it up with him while on lunch break//We talked and I pointed out that he was being misleading by still wearing his wedding band when he's a widower. He looked quite bothered by what I said but I tried to explain that I think that he was giving people the wrong idea or impression about his relationship status since he's technically single and on his own right now (don't want to sound cruel but I'm speaking from technical angle). James said that he didn't give it much thought (meaning he don't care what people think) and that even if he wasn't wearing his wedding band and some woman approached him he'd still turn them down since he's obviously not interested.//For some reason things got awkward and everyone stopped eating and just stared at James and me. I told him I don't know but that really really felt generally misleading of him as in making people think he is in a relationship (married) when he is not regardless of how he felt about being in a relationship. He got upset, called me rude, and said that I repeatedly disrespected his marriage and his late wife's memory with what I said then took his stuff and walked away. My co workers said regardless of who is right or wrong (though some said he overreacted) there was no reason for me to bring this up on the first place and cause a scene and make James upset with us like that now he's not speaking to me and others who sided with me.//AITA? Did I overstep or did he overreact?//This was just a conversation we were casually having with the other co workers and I didn't use any insensitive tones or anything but we had a discussion and it suddenly turned into an argument. I tried to let things calm down but the situation got out of my hand unexpectedly.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for threatening to quit if less experienced co-worker was promoted to be my manager" op_gender="nan" target_gender="nan" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="career consequences" good_standing="Yes" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I'm fully expecting to be judged as the AH for this one but I'm interested in hearing people's thoughts.//I'd been in this job for just under 2 years when my manager called me into their office and explained that they were being promoted and that someone on my team, who'd been in the role less than a year was going to be promoted into their role and therefore become my manager.//This came as a total shock to me and I purposefully said nothing because I didn't want to react to the news in that moment. I was confident I'd done an excellent job in that role and I'd had extremely good feedback and reviews in my time there. I respected my co-worker but I felt in little doubt they were less experienced and less capable at the job than I was. At that point I was still effectively training this person on elements of the job. I understand being good at the job isn't necessarily what makes a good manager but i felt I'd earned the right to be asked about it at the very least.//It's fair to say I was very angry about this and how it had been handled. I spoke to my manager the next day and asked why that decision had been taken. Their response was basically that I was seen as &quot;more of a do-er&quot; and that my co-worker had mentioned being interested in management at a review and that was that. If anything that made me even angrier. I explained that I was very disappointed in the decision and even more disappointed in how it was handled and that this person being my manager was not something I was willing to accept and that if they were placed in that position, I would be handing in my resignation. I genuinely meant it. This wasn't a bluff at all.//I felt like I maintained my cool during this conversation and made valid points that my manager accepted. Later that day I was told that the decision to promote my co-worker to manager had been reversed.//As time went on, I felt like my anger over this incident couldn't fade and so I found another job within 6 months of all of this happening.//I'll fully admit that what I did was largely driven by some kind of wounded pride but I don't think it was out of jealousy or pettiness. I have felt bad that I directly stopped someone I liked and respected getting a promotion but at the same time, I felt it was a poor decision, made poorly and my reaction to it was genuine.//looking forward to hearing some opinions.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling my coworker that it's not my fault that she's single when she said that it's not okay for my husband to send me gifts at our workplace?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="same" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="avoiding conflict" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I think I should clarify that he does not show up to my work to deliver the gifts in person, he usually sends me breakfast because I can't have breakfast early in the morning, so when he goes to work he stops by my favorite cafe and he orders what he knows I like and tells them where the order should be delivered. The owners are his friends so he gives them the notes to be delivered with the order.//And last but not least, I receive the order at the entrance, nobody receives the order for me, that's why I don't understand what bothers her so much.//Also, it bothers her that I put photos of my children and my husband on my desk, which doesn't even make sense because those photos are on my side of the office, sadly this is not the first time she says that I am being unprofessional (for her having photos of your children in the office is not professional) so I don't know how I should act to please her//My (26F) husband (50M) sends me gifts at work every day since we started dating, he usually sends me a rose and a coffee with a note wishing me a good day or just a note telling me that he loves me, sometimes he also sends me chocolates or food from my favorite restaurant, etc.//He's a very romantic and attentive man and I love that but my coworker (40'sF) doesn't like it at all. Yesterday he sent me some croissants and a coffee with a note saying he loved me, and when my coworker saw it she said I should tell him to stop, that it's not appropriate to receive gifts every day and another coworker told her that she was being bitter and that it's nice to have such a loving husband, that since I'm pregnant it was understandable that he spoiled me so much, but she insisted that it is not appropriate in any way, and that if he doesn't stop she will talk to our boss, she said she will tell him that she feels uncomfortable and that i'm not being professional enough and that she wants another officemate.//And that made me so mad because I'm professional enough, the things my husband sends me don't bother anyone, and they're not a distraction to me either but according to her they are. So I told her that it is not my fault that she is single and does not receive anything from anyone, that maybe if she were not so bitter someone would send her at least a coffee, and she got angry and now she told everyone that I was rude and that if I don't apologize, she will talk to HR to see &quot;what they can do with me&quot;, when I told her that I didn't think of being single as a bad thing, I only said it because she sounded like an envious person, that's all, but apparently what I said hurt her.//AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for firing my assistant after she kept making disparaging comments about pregnancy and baby related matters while I (her boss) was actually pregnant?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="exercising authority" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Edit for context and info: Yes, my assistant was given multiple warnings both verbally and official written warnings about her inappropriate comments specifically about pregnancy and to a lesser extent, babies and children. Moreover, I’m an employment and labor lawyer and the head of HR is also a lawyer so are careful to make sure everything is done properly. Regarding the eavesdropping matter, her desk is right outside my office so it is conceivable that she could overhear conversations that occur in my office. However, my office doors were shut and my husband and I were speaking very quietly. Hence, I think she intentionally eavesdropped on our conversation. Finally, I realize “unborn fetus” is not an improper term. I don’t like it as used by my assistant bc she uses it interchangeably with any inanimate object and often makes jokes about how an unborn fetus isn’t actually a real person. Thus, her use of that phrase with me was intentional.//I (39F) am pregnant with my first and am very excited by this. However my assistant, who is generally a nice person other than that this quirk, hates all things related to pregnancy, babies, and children.//I recently got in a minor car accident and had to go the hospital to make sure the baby was fine. When my husband dropped me off at my office after this incident, we discussed what we would ever do in a scenario where he would have to choose between me or the baby. I said to my husband that if it’s a choice between me or the baby, please pick the baby. Apparently my assistant eavesdropped or overheard our private conversation. After my husband left, my assistant kept saying she wanted me to understand my worth and that I, as a fully formed person, am clearly worth more than an unborn fetus.//I think probably the combination of having to try constantly to not acknowledge any aspect of my pregnancy around my assistant, her eavesdropping on very personal conversations with my husband, and finally, referring to the my future baby as an unborn fetus was just too much for me to take. Honestly, she’s actually a pretty good assistant other than this hang up she has about all things pregnancy, babies, and kids. But I couldn’t handle being around her anymore and had her terminated. AITA for this? It was a pretty cushy, relatively well paid position and I’m not sure if it was wrong of me to have terminated her over that.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for telling another employee the reason people don't like her is that she behaves like a walking, talking, Reddit-y Meme Page?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="conforming to norms" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I feel kind of bad for this, but I don't know if I should. Lori came to work for us during WFH. No one got to know her other than the brief online introductions and things shared in the group chats. She was pretty funny in the group chats, but I noticed a trend.//Lori parrots everything you expect to see on Reddit pages, Tumblr, and FB. It's hard to explain, but stuff like &quot;Oatmeal raisin cookies are the reason I have trust issues&quot; and &quot;I don't trust people who don't like dogs&quot; and all that doggo pupper goo goo ga ga pibble wibble woo woo shit, even older, dated stuff like Epic Fail or But I am Le Tired? It's all she would say.//Once we transitioned to being back in the office, I figured hey, I'm excited to get to know this woman because she must be different IRL. She's actually worse because while you expect some of the things Redditors or other &quot;online people&quot; say when you're online, in person it's just... awkward.//For example, when we were chatting in the break room (distanced, of course), she was showing pictures of her dog to people and she kept saying &quot;I don't trust people who don't LOVE dogs. Look at my doggo! He's such a good little pupper!&quot; and people were looking at her like... uh, okay. She turned to someone else and asked about their pets and the girl said &quot;Oh, I have a cat, here's a pic-&quot; and Lori just repeated &quot;UGH, I just do NOT trust people who don't like dogs. Whoever said cats were the new dog is seriously disturbed.&quot;//People started to avoid her. At one point she sat with me at lunch and talked about how she might look for a new job because the people at ours are &quot;weird&quot; and &quot;kind of mean.&quot;//I said to her, &quot;Didn't you basically yell at Jenny because she has a cat? You went on some weird awkward rant about people who don't like dogs. You think that could be part of the issue?&quot;//She got quiet and said &quot;Well there's something seriously disturbed about people who don't like dogs. It's not my fault. I don't make the rules. Why, did someone say something?&quot;//I thought for like 15 seconds and was like well, fuck it, I don't think anything is going to get through to this one. I said &quot;People don't like to talk to you because you act like a walking, talking Reddit meme page. Everything you say is just a tired, regurgitated joke from the internet. It's weird. Maybe if you stopped talking like someone who spends every day refreshing Reddit things would change?&quot;//And of course, she started to cry. She left her lunch and just went back to her cubicle and grabbed her stuff and left. She ended up taking a few days off, and when she came back she was just quiet and didn't talk to anyone. I feel bad that she feels bad, but do I really have to? AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="Aita for working on personal projects at work?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="nan" experience="nan" relationship="inferior" industry="creative" condition="no" action="stealing or misusing company resources" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="productivity decrease" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>I got caught working on personal projects during work hours yikes! But hear me out Im a graphic designer for a digital marketing agency and i run my own art business on the side. So on my day to day i have a few tasks that i need to accomplish plus all the other stuff that my coworkers request from me. That is my role, they need it, i design it, they post it.//Im fast and efficient, usually work very quickly and i finish my daily tasks ahead of time on most days. Some days are more hectic and some are super slow. So when i complete what i need to do for they day, or have a few hours to kill,instead of dicking around online on facebook or shopping like everyone else in the office i use my free time to work on my side projects.//My boss finally saw what i was doing yesterday when i got up to go to the bathroom and i left my screen on whoops. there had never been any complaints about me before but now they got me on a tight leash and threatened to reprimand me economically if i don’t stop doing it. I got a very menacing email threatening to fire me :///So my question is, is what i am doing wrong even if I still preform my job effectively and on time?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for recommending my coworker seek therapy after she blew up at work?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="labor" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="helping others" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I work 2 jobs. One is in a distribution facility, and where this took place. The coworker is this really pretty 20 or 21 year old, who is always hit on by other coworkers, and treated a certain way as such. Despite her looks and attention for it, she’s a always been a sweet, likeable, soft spoken person. Thats not me having a crush, Im an engaged 31 year old man. Thats just been the truth, which is what made her explosion all the more shocking. For privacy, Ill call her Maria. So Maria has been quieter than usual the past few days, but otherwise been acting fine. So I already suspected something could be wrong.//However 2 days ago, this guy had been rushing to a dock with a handjack and accidentally bumped her with it, and said “excuse me!” in this rough tone. What made things strange was what she said in her reaction. She BLEW UP, uncharacteristic enough, but she shouted “IM TIRED OF FUCKING MEN ACTING LIKE YOU CAN TREAT ME LIKE SHIT! IM THE PRETTIEST FUCKING THING ALIVE! WHY THE FUCK DO YOU THINK YOU CAN TREAT ME LIKE THIS?” and basically stuff along those lines. It was extremely weird because no one ever heard her talk like this so most people were quietly working while she and him went back and forth. Then she started crying and walked off.//Instead of being put off by what she said, I thought maybe it was some mental breakdown, because shes not a conceited girl at all. So yesterday, a day after the incident and after both parties spoke to management, I pulled her aside to talk to her and tell her Im not necessarily the best person to understand whatever it is shes going through, but I have a therapist she can call. This was out of genuine concern. She seemed appreciative when I spoke to her and even thanked me, but I guess somehow she didnt take it as well as I thought because she went around crying to coworkers and a supervisor that I was being condescending, making fun of her and starting more drama. So then I got called to the office with Maria and two supervisors and it was my word vs hers. They took hers.//The problem is that people think I was doing it to be an instigator, and Im in trouble for it. This is easy for ppl to believe bc Ive always been the “funny” guy, but I can sometimes have a hot temper too. Thats just my personality. Humor has always been a coping mechanism. But I was not joking with her. Still, today, I ended up in a heated argument with a different coworker (Bree) about how I should’ve just stayed in my place and that ended in me calling her out of her name, and saying derogatory things, and me getting written up for both incidents, which I know that part was out of line but she wasnt minding her business either. So now the attention shifted from the initial incident to me vs Bree and Maria and Bree is trying to build a case against me saying she felt threatened.//Anyway, WITA for giving the therapist recommendation, despite me doing it out of pure concern, or should I have actually just stayed out of it?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA(38M) for telling an employee(28F) that she needs to dress more conservatively?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="exercising authority" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>So I run a small startup, we’re growing but still under 30 employees. Hence, we don’t really have an HR person yet. We do have somewhat of a laid back office environment. Ton of games, snacks, and everyone dresses casually. One of our new hires is a great developer. Definitely one of our best as it’s turning out. She’s a great addition to the team and everyone loves her, however, my one complaint with her is how she dresses. I feel like she takes our casual dress code too far.//She often wears see-through shirts with just a bra underneath or non see-through shirts with no bra and her nipples poking out. We have current clients and potential clients stop by at our office all the time. No ones says anything outright but I’ve seen some clients raise eyebrows at her apparel and have heard some of the guys at work make jokes like “wow it sure must be chilly in here” when she’s out of earshot. Again, she’s a great developer and really smart girl and I do want to keep her on board. It’s just awkward because we don’t have an HR department to talk to her.//I’ve tried having a general conversation with everyone a couple weeks back reminding them to keep it professional when the clients are in the building however she didn’t seem to get the memo. Last week I finally pulled her aside and point blank told her that she needs to stop wearing see through shirts and make sure her nipples aren’t visible and that her bottoms are close to knee length. Conversation did not go well and she accused me of sexism because I never admonished any of the guys on their outfits. But the guys wear things like cargo shorts and T-shirt’s, like I said I’m okay with casual-wear. I told her if they walked in with tank tops or something I’d also call them out. AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA (60M) for making my coworker (16F) cry at workj" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="Yes" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Just to clarify i made a new account so the drama doesn’t go to my main.//Hey, Reddit! I need some honest opinions on a situation that recently unfolded at my workplace, and I want to know if I'm the asshole in this scenario.//I (60M) work at a Burger King, and for the most part, my coworkers and I get along well. We have our occasional disagreements, but we usually sort them out like adults. However, last week, I found myself in a situation that escalated beyond my intentions.//We were having a busy shift, and the stress was getting to all of us. Our coworker, Jane (16F), was a bit slower than usual due to being new on the job. I was already on edge due to the constant rush of customers and my own personal issues. In a moment of frustration, I lashed out at Jane in front of everyone, criticizing her for being too slow and making mistakes.//I didn't intend to make her cry, but my words were harsh and hurtful, and she ended up breaking down in tears. The rest of my coworkers were shocked, and one of them took Jane to the back to comfort her. I felt terrible immediately after seeing her reaction, and I did apologize later that day. Jane accepted my apology, but the incident left a tense atmosphere at work.//I can't help but feel guilty for letting my emotions get the best of me. Yes, it was a stressful day, but that's not an excuse for treating a coworker that way, especially someone who is still learning the ropes. Some of my friends have told me that I was just having a bad day and shouldn't beat myself up over it, while others think I was completely out of line.//So, Reddit, tell me honestly, am I the asshole for making my coworker cry? Should I be doing more to make things right, or is this something that can be chalked up to a bad day and move on from? I'm open to your thoughts and criticisms. Thanks in advance.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling my co-worker why I don't use our company health insurance?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="healthcare" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I (F27) was having a casual conversation with a coworker (M50s) and he brought up that the enrollment period for our company insurance was coming to an end and asked me if I had finished signing up yet. I responded by saying &quot;Oh, I use my husband's insurance. Our company is opposed to reproductive rights and only covers birth control when mandated by law&quot;. He said something along the lines of &quot;I guess you need some type of control&quot; and we moved on to talking about the technical work that we were doing.//Later in the afternoon I got an email from my boss (M26) and he said that I shouldn't talk about details of my personal life with my co-worker and it made people uncomfortable.//My thought is that equal rights only happen when people are willing to make it a part of mainstream conversation. AITA for responding truthfully, but possibly with a bit TMI to a conversation started by my co worker, or should I have just kept it at &quot;Oh, I use my husband's insurance&quot; and not finished the sentence?//Edit: There was one other person in the room when I made the comment (also M50s). My boss didn't say who, but my belief is that it is the other person in the room who made the complaint, not the one I was actually talking to.//Edit 2: Wow, a lot more attention than I thought. First, a lot of questions about my work. I work for a hospital owned by a catholic conglomerate that employs about 125k people. I accepted the job when it was my only career related option for work, and it can be hard to leave. I wish I could work for someone with all the same ideals as I have, but then I would probably just be self employed. There are several people in my department who are openly non christian religions, and LGBTQ+. Just because it is a catholic organization does not mean it directly reflects the views of many of the employees.//I spoke with my boss today. He was promoted from being my co-worker about a month ago and is still semi transitioning into his first management job. He apologized for his email without discussing with me and I apologized for my combative tone in the work place. He mentioned that our company policy includes harassments to include conversations that make people uncomfortable when they are within ear shot even if they are not directed at them (which confirmed my suspicion) but also conceded that what I said would not be considered harassment. I apologized for taking such a combative stance and said I will try to be more cognizant of my tone and audience in the future. He said that he never made an official statement to HR and was addressing this as a disagreement between coworkers. I also believe my other coworker's statement was a sort of &quot;clumsy agreement&quot; with me as I saw in the comments, not an attack at me, so I did not mention it. I have a summary of our conversation in email and saved. I doubt he handled it the best or most officially, but in the interest of an amicable work place, I have left it at that, have my documentation, and don't intend to follow it any further on my end.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling my manager about a creepy coworker" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I'm a (17f) working in a fast food restaurant. When I first met my coworker, let's call him Bob (18m), he seemed cool and nice. However, things started getting weird about three months into working with him. Bob would make suggestive comments, jokes, and be overly flirty, which made me uncomfortable. He also became more touchy and would hovering and stare at me unnecessarily.//After a six-week break for school exams and extracurricular activities, I returned to work. Bob's behavior became worse and more frequent. Bob even took a shift with me on a day he never works and during a time he us usually doesn’t work. While I was doing dishes alone in the back, Bob was being annoying and asked me to take out the trash for him when it was his job to do so I got annoyed and told him off, reminding him that it was his job. He then started spraying water on me with a hose, saying “bad girl” I somehow managed to keep my cool and asked him to give the hose back so I could continue cleaning.//At that point, I was fed up and frustrated, so I waited until my General Manager (GM) came to the back. I told my GM about Bob's behavior, how he made me uncomfortable, and mentioned that I might tell him off if it continued (although I wouldn't actually do that). My GM immediately intervened and told Bob to stop and my GM told me to immediately tell him if Bob continues. After that, Bob acted coldly towards me, and the rest of the staff seemed unresponsive for the rest of the shift.//Important Notes: I didn't explicitly tell Bob that I was uncomfortable, but I gave him hints through body language, tone of voice, and uninterested responses. Bob only acted this way when no females were around, as this was an all-male shift so it was just a recipe for disaster.//This incident happened on June 23, and I'm writing this on June 24, right after my midnight shift ended. I feel confused and unsure about what to do next.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for talking about being food insecure at work" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I (M22) am a substitute teacher. In my district we're paid the legal minimum for the job. If you work more than 15 days at a school you get &quot;normal&quot; pay - I only ever get jobs that are exactly 15 days. A few days into my placement, I heard some teachers (both M30ish) in the lounge complaining that bus monitors only get paid $20 an hour, and laughing about how only an idiot would do a job for that little. I make $14.50. I jumped in and told them, they didn't know I was being paid that little.//My monthly grocery budget is $150. An entire paycheck has to go to rent alone, and then the majority of the rest goes to medical expenses (I am permanently disabled), other bills, and gas. I usually have less than $10 total for a few days before my next paycheck. I don't qualify for SNAP. My disabilities make most food pantry items inaccessible (I have anaphylaxis from nuts, honey, peppers, and more). For the past month, thanks to a prescription going up in price, I have been eating once every 24 hours to keep making rent, but for the last 8 months I've been food insecure. I usually cry on the way home because I pass by fast food and know I can't even get a hamburger. I'm almost always so hungry it hurts.//I admit I've got some resentment to my job for paying me so little while the school constantly complains that we don't have enough subs. I've had anger building up over the fact that I'm starving, and they only hire me for the maximum days before they have to pay me more.//Where I might be the asshole://I've started being open about the fact that I'm hungry at work. I never ask for food – just stuff like they'll ask if I can keep a student in the room over lunch, and I'll be chipper/my usual self and reply &quot;of course, I'll just be reading, I couldn't afford food today.&quot; A teacher I don't know will ask what I packed for lunch and I'll say &quot;nothing, I can't afford that much food.&quot; Stuff like that. It's always true. I'm careful to not exaggerate.//Recently I was in the library and the librarian asked if I had dinner plans. I said no, I have to skip eating today because I can't afford it. She looked at me weird and said while she won't judge me for being unable to eat, it's very unprofessional to talk about it at work where you're being paid. I told her if it's unprofessional for me to talk about starving it's just as unprofessional to pay me so little I starve. She went quiet and we didn't really talk for the rest of the day.//She got me thinking and I'll admit I don't know if I'm actually being an asshole. I know other staff aren't the ones who pay me so little. But I also feel like my struggle is invisible, and after full time teachers called anyone taking even $20 an hour an idiot, it's really been eating at me (ha).//TL;DR I'm being open about the fact that I'm food insecure at work, and don't feel bad for making the people paid more than me feel awkward. I was told it was unprofessional and snapped back.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="Aita for calling my coworker creepy and gross and getting him in trouble?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="lower" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="seeking fairness or justice" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>So Im 23f and I started this job a few months ago. Im the only woman in our department of about 30 people. This one guy 50s male has been telling me about all the younger women he's slept with and making insinuations towards me. He kept telling me how he pleasures women. I tried to be nice and ignore it, I tried saying I wasn't interested and he just kept going. Finally I lost my patience and snapped at him. I told him he was creepy and gross and that I was never going to be interested in some old man 30 years my senior. Management overheard and pulled me aside to find out what happened. I told them about his comments to me and he was written up for sexual harassment. This is his second write up (the first was for injuring someone.) he's been at this job a lot longer then me and now half the department is angry with me because he is about to be fired and they think its my fault and the other half are on my side. They said I &quot;didn't have to be such a bitch about it&quot; and that &quot;he's like that with girls he finds attractive and I should be flattered&quot; and &quot;I shouldn't have yelled at him because now management is involved&quot; Work is really uncomfortable now because half of our department doesnt want to work with me.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for giving a very silly ugly smile in meetings after my boss said I should smile more?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="inferior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="retaliation" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="No" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I work in a tech consulting job, I'm the only woman on the team.. and my boss told me I was coming off &quot;harsh&quot; with clients and should be more upbeat and smile more. It felt... Ick//I right away texted my group chat of coworkers (without the management in it) asking &quot;has BossMan ever told any of you guys to smile more?'//It was an immediate round of no's, and a couple of my coworkers asked if he said that to me and pointed out the double standard. A few of my coworkers joked that some of the clients we have right now don't give them anything to smile about.//So then I asked if any of them had ever been called harsh, and it was again all nos.//I told them that the boss had told me to smile more, and one of my coworkers sent me a picture of a girl pulling a silly face with a weird pinched smile and bug-out eyes saying &quot;well what BossMan says, he gets&quot;//I thought that was hilarious and decided to actually do it.//Anyway, I started smiling more and more around my boss... But also a bit stupidly. Just keeping my mouth pinched tensely, gums on display, and purposely pulling my chin back towards my neck so I'd get a double chin.//I never did it in front of actual clients, just my boss and coworkers who were in on the joke. And my boss kept looking uncomfortable when I did.//He asked me at a meeting about a week in what that face I was pulling was. I said &quot;Uhh what face&quot; He said &quot;That one, just a second ago&quot; and my coworker said &quot;What, she was just smiling? What are you getting at her for?&quot;//My boss said&quot;It looked like she was pulling a face&quot; and my other coworker pulled out his phone where he had some pictures from a recent happy hour where I was pulling that face to make my coworkers laugh. And he said &quot;Dude, what the hell is wrong with you, that's literally her smile? Look at this picture from last Friday&quot; and all of my coworkers backed him up saying that was just how I smile.//My boss was looking kinda incredulous so I clarified that if something makes me spontaneously laugh or grin, it probably looks a little more relaxed, but when I'm just putting on a smile to be polite or pose for a picture, I guess that's how I smile. And I was trying to be polite after he let me know I was coming off &quot;harsh&quot; in meetings.//Anyway, at my next one on one meeting, my boss said I didn't need to change my demeanor that much based on his comments, because honestly it was coming off disengenous and that would look worse in front of clients.//I just said &quot;Yeah, I guess I've never really been good at being super peppy without it looking fake.&quot;//And as far as I know, that was the end of that. Except for it becoming a running joke at the offce that I look like Nigel Thornberry. Which is a pretty smashing nickname honestly.//But I feel a little bad that I basically gaslit my boss and my coworkers were in on it instead of being direct with him and just saying that he was coming across a bit sexist.//AITA for my fake smile thing?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for getting mad at my coworker who asked me “why are you so quiet?”" op_gender="M" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="retaliation" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Ok so I’m not a very talkative person AT ALL. I hate small talk, I don’t like talking about myself and I’m not particularly interested in other people either. It seems like every workplace I go to people think I’m weird because I don’t socialize. I’m not rude or anything, I just don’t go out of my way to have conversations with people I’d rather listen to my music. The other day while I was on lunch break one of my coworkers just randomly asks me while I’m minding my own business “why are you always so quiet man? You never say nothing!”. and immediately I got so pissed off. Without thinking I responded “same reason why you’re so loud” and he was all like “yo man relax it was just a question”. Then I said “is there a problem or…?” and he said “alright never mind man I’ll leave you alone” and that was that.//I feel like I was unnecessarily rude here but it’s just I’m so sick of people asking me that question and making it sound like an accusation. It’s like being quiet is a bad thing to them or it means there’s something wrong with me. Like why even ask someone that? I know I could’ve just said something like “oh idk” or “it’s just the way I am” but why should I have to explain why I’m minding my own business? Still I took out my anger on this guy when it really wasn’t about him, it was the fact I’ve been asked that stupid question so many times that annoyed me.//If I am the asshole, should I apologize to him? This happened recently enough that it wouldn’t look weird to apologize for it.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for refusing to spend any of my money on clients at work?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Hey Reddit, feeling pretty annoyed right now and seeking some clarity on a situation. I recently turned 24 and work in a Transitional Housing Facility with a small group of clients who are transitioning out of foster care.//Angie (34F) is my colleague, and we work the same shift from noon to 8 PM. Angie has formed close relationships with two of the clients, Jilly and Emma, who are both 18 years old.//Every Friday, Angie takes the clients to a coffee shop in the next town over to enjoy live music. She pays for their dinner, coffee, and even helps them get ready by doing their hair and providing makeup. Now, here's where things take a turn.//Angie dropped the bombshell a few days ago that she will be teaching a class at another facility, which means she won't be available for the coffee shop outings for the next few weeks. Today, Emma and Jilly approached me about the upcoming coffee shop outing, assuming I would be taking them. I was caught off guard because this arrangement was never discussed with me.//Feeling frustrated, I approached Angie to clarify the situation. I made it clear that I had no intention of taking over the outings. After all, my shift ends at 8 PM, and I prefer not to be out late at night. Furthermore, driving has always been a stressful experience for me, and I would rather not take on that responsibility unless it's absolutely necessary. Using my personal vehicle for work-related tasks is also not something I'm comfortable with.//I have taken clients to coffee before, but it was while driving the company vehicle, using donated money to buy the coffee. I don't spend a dime of my own money on anyone at work. I also refuse to drive people in my won car. Usually this is not an issue, because the company car is available.//But Angie will be taking that car, and the company card. This means I would be expected to pay my own money, gas, the coffee for them (because they do not have money). This is not something I am willing to do.//I don't think it's fair to expect me to compromise my boundaries and put myself in a stressful situation because of that. On top of that, Angie laid into me, claiming that &quot;everyone helps out with their own money,&quot; which I find to be an unreasonable expectation.//So, Reddit, I need your perspective. Am I the jerk for refusing to take over Angie's outing duties?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for forwarding someone's email to their boss and probably getting him fired?" op_gender="M" target_gender="M" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="yes" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="seeking fairness or justice" impact="career consequences" good_standing="Yes" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I work in sales, in my industry there's a lot of resentment towards sales because of the potential income you can make. That being said it's all commission based, I know a number of sales guys who have second jobs to make ends meet. I've always tried to be an operations friendly sales person. I know the reputation sales people have, and I try to not be that way. I stop by the office once or twice a month with beer and pizza for operations, I've given the kid who works on all my orders a 1k bonus more than a handful of times when I've closed big deals, I give small Christmas gifts to everyone that does anything for me in the office. Small things like that, and I never stress deadlines as long as we're within a week or two of meeting them, I really try to be the easiest person you can work with.//My mentor who made me the salesman I am today sometimes funnels sales through me since he's retired. The company knows, no one has an issue and I owe the guy my professional career so I do these deals for nothing. I do all the legwork, get nothing and pay taxes on the income. It's not much and I'm comfortable so it's not a big deal. I recently closed a sale for him that was a nightmare, I mean the worst customer I've ever dealt with. At one point I had to cut a scheduled vacation with friends to Vegas short halfway through because the sale would have fallen through if I didn't. Again I never mentioned this to anyone just closed the sale. My mentor made more than I've made from any deal on that deal, as always he offered me a cut but I told him there's no way I'd accept it and moved on. While operations don't see what we make on deals, the assumption is usually the bigger the sale the bigger the commission. That's not always the case but they don't know that. When I closed this sale the kid I work with was hinting that he expected a huge bonus from me for this sale. I laughed and told him sorry bud, nothing thing time, I made nothing on this sale. I could tell right away that he didn't like that answer and the conversation ended shortly after that. I assumed he was just bummed, which was fine.//The next day I got a long email from him going on and on about how hard he works, and how he doesn't make a quarter of what I make a year, and if it wasn't for him I couldn't close a single sale. Honestly I skimmed it, forwarded it to his boss and with a single sentence that read &quot;This can never happen again.&quot; I found out the next day they suspended the guy and are considering firing him. I conveyed to his boss that I liked working with the kid and didn't want to see him fired for 1 mistake but was told that my input wasn't needed. AITA for possibly getting this kid fired?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for telling my coworker to put his phone away?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="inferior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="exercising authority" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>Every morning at work before we open, my manager(40sF) will have a meeting with all of the employees to give us a rundown for the day and update us on things as needed. I (24F) am a manager on duty and have been working there for about 2 years.//One morning, when she was talking during the meeting, I noticed one of our employees texting nonstop on his phone. He (30sM) was sitting behind a cubicle wall out of sight from my manager, so I don’t think she noticed him being on his phone the entire time. It seemed that he was not listening to what she was saying at all, and not once did he put his phone down.//After a few more minutes of this, when there was a slight pause in the meeting, I asked him to please put away his phone while the manager is talking. He did put his phone down, and my manager rolled her eyes at me but kept talking.//A few days later, the manager came up to me, saying she needed to talk to me about something. I said okay, and she brought up this situation and how I was wrong and shouldn’t have told the employee to put his phone away. She said what I did was hurting my relationships with the employees (more context in a second) and that I should have left the situation for her to take care of. I explained that I felt that it was disrespectful towards her that an employee was texting/on their phone while she was talking during the meeting, and she said that it didn’t matter and wasn’t my problem. I was extremely hurt by this, but said okay.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for being angry that a coworker for giving customers personal information about employees?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>Update: First, during her training, and everytime she has dome something like this I have told her to stop, and not di it again. I discussed this with my boss, again. I've told him, and her multiple times this isn't ok. Little did I know he's had multiple conversations with her about it as well. After he caught her telling a customer about why a coworkers is on leave last week, he contacted HR about this ongoing issue. He had me forward him the email I received, and she's being formally written up on Monday.//Thanks for the responses, and those who said this IS a legal issue! I told my boss this, and he told me HR told him that last week. He got a slap on the wrist for not writing her up sooner.//Pretty self explantory. Our first desk employee consistly tells customers when an employee is out of the office, exactly why they're not it. Examples: surgery, covid, getting married, family issue, that kind of thing. She's been asked not to do that by other employees, but it doesn't sink in. I haven't really pressed the issue. I was the person that trained her when I got promoted. I made it clear this is a not ok. My boss has pretty much left me to handle issues with her me, unless it's something major. Well now I'm angry.//I had to leave work early on Wednesday to pick my daughter up from school due to being sick (strep). One of my appointments couldn't be rescheduled for one of my coworkers agreed go get the pictures I needed, and I would email the customer the following day. We do this for each other when needed. I took care of this when I returned yesterday.//I just got a response from my customer, and the first line of the email was how he was told I had left early because my child was sick to pick her up, and he hoped she felt better. I appreciate the sentiment, but that is not information ANY customer should have, for any reason. I'm angry that instead of telling the customer I had emergency, the front desk person gave specifics, AGAIN. AITA for being angry about this, or am I being ridiculous?//Edit: I'm sorry for confusion so let me fix it. Am I pissed that this happened to me? Yes of course. I've never even physically met this customer, and they knew it was my daughter being the reason I left. I'm annoyed because I keep telling her to stop this. She did get told by the boss to knock it off when he caught her telling a customer about a coworkering being out for surgery, as well as the type of surgery. I'm going to forward the email to HR, and explain this is not a one time thing.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for not telling my employer that I can only work for a month" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="yes" action="telling the truth" intention="avoiding conflict" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I just finished high school and wanted to work during the summer to save up some money for uni. I applied at a retail store. I wanted to work for two months but when I applied for this specific job it took them a month to get back to me. They offered me the job and I took it. It’s my second week now and I went to give my two week notice.//I told the manager that I can’t work in September and any further that. She asked me if I was quitting and I said yes. Then she asked me why, and I said because of school. She asked me when I started working and I said the beginning of last week. Then she asked me did you say you could only work for a month during your interview. And I said no. Then she went on to say that it was very dishonest of me, and very unfair to the company, that I should’ve told them during the interview that they wouldn’t have hired me, and that this is going to be very bad for my future. I then said I’m really sorry. Then she kinda chuckled and said how can you be sorry you already knew you were going to do this.//I feel really bad now.//Edit: just for more info, the manager I talked to isn't the main manager. I had asked to see the store manager, but I personally don't know what type of manager she is but she told me she could help. Then afterwards she said I'd have to talk to the store manager. I'm probably going to have to go through this again tomorrow :|. After this, I'm super nervous to even put in the 2 weeks.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for not sharing my study materials with my coworkers when my boss asked me to?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="nan" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I work as an engineer in a highly-respected company. Our division has recently hired some less-than-impressive employees, some 10-25 years ahead of myself in the field. We are expected to spend about a year studying for a certification exam that is known to be grueling; I spent many nights and weekends creating study materials for myself and recently passed the test.//These seasoned engineers are in a new specialty and don't seem eager to return to studying. My supervisor asked me to share my personal materials and lead study sessions with everyone (during work hours). While I respect and get along with the new employees on a personal level, I think they should have to put in the work like I did. I jokingly said something along the lines of &quot;Do I have to do everything around here?&quot; and am pretty sure I fucked up.//I've been trying to be more assertive since I have a history of letting people take advantage of me and my work... but perhaps this was not the right move. Reddit, AITA?//ETA: All study materials were made on my own time with source material I paid for myself. The expectation is that you are hired having already passed the cert exam, but if not, you have one year after hire to pass it.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for accidentally calling out a new colleague on lying about her language skills?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="damage to reputation" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Last week a new colleague &quot;Cathy&quot; (33f) started at my (25f) work place. She instantly stood out in the team, because she seems like someone who is very... loud and assertive? Two of my colleagues, me and Cathy were having coffee in the break room (we were the only ones in there and we were sitting far apart), when the subject of travel was brought up. My colleague said she wasn't booking trips anymore because it'll probably get cancelled because of covid anyway. Cathy, immediately cut in about how sad she is because she travels so often and she goes on these far &quot;exotic&quot; trips to Europe as her hobby. When I think exotic I think the Bahamas or something instead of Europe but. Cool.//Cathy then jokes about how all this &quot;no travel business&quot; is making her fear that she'll lose some of her foreign language skills. I asked what languages she spoke. She claimed to be fluent in 3 European languages, among which were French and Dutch. Cathy said she was &quot;at a native speaker level&quot; and went on about how people in Europe were always surprised when they found out she wasn't from there.//I was excited, because I never get to speak Dutch over here. I was raised in Belgium, which has three national languages: French and Dutch (which are my mother tongues and the most commonly spoken there) and German. It's quite common to be pretty fluent in at least two out of the three languages in Belgium, because you're required to learn them at school (along with English) from a young age. I told Cathy &quot;oh leuk, dan hebben we iets gemeenschappelijk!&quot; (&quot;oh fun, we have something in common then!&quot;)//She immediately pulled this sour face and asked me if that was supposed to be Dutch. I said yes. She laughed awkwardly and said she &quot;couldn't understand because I have a terrible accent and must not be that good at speaking it.&quot; Now see, I don't have an accent. I speak Dutch more fluently than I speak English. I told Cathy that I grew up speaking Dutch and speak it to my family all the time.//She got miffed and asked what languages I speak and where I'm from. I told her I'm from Belgium, so I also speak French and I added &quot;which you just said you speak as well, cool! We can speak French instead!&quot; I acknowledge that I was a bit of a dick here, because by that point I knew she probably lied about speaking French as well. She then shoved her chair back and angrily got up, said &quot;whatever&quot; and stomped off. It was awkward. My other colleagues just kinda shrugged and said she shouldn't have lied.//However, she later approached me and told me I embarrassed her by acting &quot;superior&quot; about my European heritage. I told her there was no way for me to know she'd lied about speaking those languages. She rolled her eyes and told me I was immature. A colleague told me that Cathy had called me a &quot;little b-word who enjoys bullying new colleagues&quot; behind my back later. I don't think I was a bully at all, but I don't want this to turn into a huge thing. Do I just apologize to keep the peace? AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for refusing to help a coworker." op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="same" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="making or declining requests" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I(28F) am single, don't have kids and live alone. I also do not work OT or do anything beyond my work. Also I am not in the US.//First let me explain what my work is like: so we are an internal auditing company. I work in the logistics auditing division. What that means is that when a company hires us (mostly to see how good their policies are), we shadow their workers, to see where efficiency can be increased. Sometimes that means working night shift, delivery, warehouse, manufacturing...etc.//We are very lucky that we have an awesome manager and team leader. Once we divide the tasks, you can do them whenever as long as you report is handed when it should be. Work from home, from the office, at 3am, less than 40hrs... It doesn't matter.//For the 6 years I have been on this team, another female coworker (30s) has been doing her absolute best to work the least amount possible. First she is either always pregnant and not &quot;able&quot; to shadow anyone but the office workers, she is on maternity leave (4 months), on her yearly vacation (a month), or conveniently sick when it is time for some heavy duty work (she sends in a doctor's notice, and we have unlimited PTO as long as you have a doctor's notice). And we she is in the office, she is dumping her work on the others. She uses her kids as an excuse all the time.//Well usually the other team members pick up her slack, I refuse to do so.//This time we are auditing a larger company, so all hands on deck. And for the first time ever she is neither pregnant nor on maternity leave, and she just got back from her yearly leave.//The company we are auditing is in another city, so the members who will have to go will be staying there for 3 weeks. This time it is my turn to stay in the office (well my home TBH) and do the data organisation/analysis.//She asked me to switch with her, apparently she can't leave her 5 kids alone with her husband. I said no. She tried to guilt trip me by saying that what she would have to pay for child care is more than what she would get paid for the whole month, and that I don't have any responsibilities like her. I told her &quot;well they are not my kids, so I don't see how that is my problem&quot;//Now she is pouting like a kid, and some coworkers are saying that I don't know how hard working moms have it, that I should be more compassionate.//So AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for refusing to eat from my colleague's vegan birthday cake?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I (29f) am working in an office and I have a colleague Bea, who routinely makes fun of vegans. I am vegan and i never make a fuss about food, i go to the same restaurants as my coworkers during lunch hour and i can always find myself something to eat without announcing my dietary choices. Bea keeps calling me out on it though and she's very condescending about it, she keeps saying i am just having a phase and she keeps offering me bites of her lunch that contain cheese and meat, and when i refuse she just goes &quot;oh come on, its vegan i promise!&quot; winkwink. Its very childish and annoying and even other people asked her to tone it down, but she insists shes just joking.//Last week she brought a homemade cake to the office for her birthday, and when she put a slice down in front of me i politely thanked her but i said i cant eat that. She said the cake is vegan and she made it specifically so i could eat it, but knowing her very loose definition of vegan i asked a few questions about the ingredients and she didnt check any of them for milk or eggs, so I thanked her again but refused the slice. She made a big scene out of it, she started crying and saying she just wanted to do something nice for me and now i ruined her birthday.//Some colleagues told me not to mind her dramatics, but my boss told me that it was her birthday and i could have given her cooking the benefit of the doubt. I sort of see his point, but i also feel like i dont need to justify my food choices to anyone and i never asked her to make the cake vegan for me.//AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for refusing to hand over my phone to my boss to check the message I sent?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="inferior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>My f26 3yo son got sick and I had to take him to the hospital in the mornjng. I took an hour off work and texted my boss letting him know why.//I arrived to work later and my boss requested to see me in his office. He started questioning me about being late but I told him I already sent him a text telling him why. He said he didn't recieve anything but I assured him that I sent it. He told me to hand over my phone so he could check but I refused. I asked him to check his phone but he again denied recieving anything and said there was no point in checking his inbox. He asked that I hand over my phone to see the text I sent but I still refused and suggested that I open the text and show it to him because I have private messages with my boyfrirnd that I fidn't anybody to see, let alone my boss. He refused to ler me show him saying I might be faking it but I already have the time and date of the text(?). He got mad and insisted that I hand it over. I declined and said no, this is my privacy and he does not get to violate it just because he has authority over me. He got more upset and told me to step outside. Aftee making me wait for 30+ minutes. He had his female assistant try to convince me to let him &quot;have a quick look&quot; but I refused. The argument escalated and I was told to go home til this is figured out. My boss is angry with me and his assistant is claiming that it was such a weird hill to die on and that if I truely fid send him a message then I should just let him have a look.//AITA? I mean I offered him alternative way to see the text but he insisted on checking it himself. I'm an extremly private person and the thought of him peeking at private, vulnerable conversations with my boyfriend makes uncomfortable. My boyfriend thinks I should've just given it to him without making a scene.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for reporting my coworker to HR?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="healthcare" condition="yes" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="following rules" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="No" perspective="No">
		<content>I work in a hospital and pranks are a big part of the culture and “bonding” I don’t like it and don’t get involved.//There is a doctor at the hospital “Tory” who I’ve always got the vibe didn’t like me. Tory was showering the other day to go home and another doctor we work with convinced the resident “Annie” to grab Tory’s clothes and soak them in water. It was semi cold out and Tory understandably wasn’t happy (though she gets involved in the stupidity so I don’t feel bad)//Tory called her a cunt which I didn’t think was appropriate. Annie is pregnant and Tory said I hope your baby is stupid, then said I hope your baby has cognitive issues. Annie laughed and asked if she was dancing around saying a certain word and Tory said I hope your baby is “on every spectrum” and “too dumb to function” and then she said the baby probably wasn’t going to be pretty because of who the dad was.//Annie laughed but I was appalled. I feel like the lack of empathy and the language was really concerning and I reported her. Long story short nothing was done, Tory officially hates me, and I was told it was a dumb decision and I clearly don’t know who Tory is dating (I don’t actually) Now Tory is very rude to me and Annie and the guy who told her to do it avoid me. I feel like a might have overreacted but at the same time I really believe Tory needs sensitivity training and some harsh consequences because I wouldn’t want someone who talks like that as my doctor.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for not sympathizing with my work friend and telling her she should know better?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="telling the truth" intention="retaliation" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>25M I work a mundane office job in middle corporate America and spent most days hating whatever decisions I made to get me to this point. One of the people I am closer with is “Ash” 24F. We are the only people under 30 in the office so that’s why we’ve gotten closer.//Yesterday, we had our “spring cleaning” day. This is where we were instructed to wear comfy clothes we can beat up in order to clean the office. We were instructed to wear jeans and a t shirt or whatever was comfortable and similar to that. No sweat pants though.//The short version is that Ash was called into our bosses office and spoken to about her outfit choice. Which was jeans and a cropped sweater. I guess they just told her that wearing a cropped sweater that went just above her navel was inappropriate work attire even in a situation like this. Boss gave her an old t shirt with the company logo to change into.//Ash spent the next 30 minutes yapping my fricking ear off about how it’s unfair, sexist, and embarrassing that she was spoken to about her outfit. She said she was wearing jeans, and wore a comfortable top that she could get dirty and that is exactly what boss said we should wear.//After growing tired of listening to her, I told her that i don’t feel bad for her and that she made a dumb decision. She accused me of being as “sexist” as our boss. I told her she’s in a corporate job, and she’s not 16 so frankly she should know better and that it doesn’t take a genius to know you should probably have shoulders to knees covered in a work setting.//I know I didn’t put it kindly, but she was also yapping for awhile and I just couldn’t understand how she didn’t see this coming. So am I THE ass opening?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling my manager that if her pregnancy is effecting her decision making then she shouldn't be in her position?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="inferior" industry="labor" condition="yes" action="telling the truth" intention="seeking fairness or justice" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Some context: I am a 27F working in a factory, my position involves sorting mail and dealing with returns and damages. I started my position making $14 which was more then what the truck loaders were making but once minimum wage increased to $14 my pay didn't increase. I was denied a raise and was told that my position was no more important then theirs.//Current issue: I'm taking a week of vacation, my manager Heather aggressively confronted me saying that it was really inconsiderate of me to take that much time off and that it's unprofessional for my position. I told her that I make just as much a loaders and they wouldn't be questioned for using their vacation week. She said that my position is imortant and not as easily filled while I'm gone. I said that I was told otherwise and that if she felt that way then I should be compensated as such.//Later in the day she came back and apologized saying that she's five months pregnant and hormones are making her emotional but that I put her in a very bad spot and that I need reconsider taking my vacation. I told her that she's the one that approved my vacation months ago and if her pregnancy is effecting her behavior and decision making then maybe she shouldn't be in her position.//She left very uspet and told my coworkers that I said she wasn't fit for her job because she's pregnant and that I was acting all high and mighty asking for a raise. I've got a lot people calling me an asshole and a few agreeing me. AITA?//Update: I just got off work and went to Heathers office to apologize but a lead told me she left crying. So Heather told everyone in the office what happened and they took Heather off floor management and scheduling, another manager Alex apologized to me for her behaviour and told me that she was supposed to have someone there for the week I'm off but forgot and tried getting me to rescedual, and that it was inappropriate to do so. Should I still text her and apologize?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for gluing a coin to the floor in my workplace?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="M" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="labor" condition="no" action="stealing or misusing company resources" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>Each day, over a hundred people walk back and forth through my work area. It's a manufacturing facility with polished concrete flooring. I had the idea to Gorilla-glue a $2 coin (Toonie) to the floor by the designated walkway.//The first morning, pretty much everybody noticed the coin. Some ignored it but most people bent down and tried to pick it up. Fruitlessly, of course. Later in the day people brought tools in yet another vain attempt to displace the coin. Now it's all dented and mashed up. Throughout the day I discreetly watched people struggle to get the coin loose and quite enjoyed myself.//One of the bosses (who isn't fit to run a lemonade stand) eventually found out about the coin and asked a tradesman to drill it out of the floor or otherwise remove it. Tradesman told him, &quot;I've got better things to do, take a walk.&quot; So the coin is still there and people are still falling victim.//Since then, at our morning meeting, it was mentioned to all employees not to glue things to company property (as if I'm going to go around gluing things to walls, equipment, etc.) It's a one-shot deal but the boss who has nothing better to do really wants to find the culprit. I have a hard time believing I'm not the asshole here, but at the same time I'm also donating $2 to anyone who can successfully remove the coin.//Okay, lay it on me.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for reporting my colleague to HR?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="lower" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>Background: I (26f) just started my first job after finishing my masters, and work in a dept with another colleague (27f, Thea) who joined the company 2 months before me. She is currently in graduate school, and I'm amazed at how she is very efficient and fast in her tasks.//I noticed that Thea is always assigned complicated tasks despite being new to the company, and I wanted to join the projects that she's in so I can learn from her. Initially, Thea was fine with it, and I learned that she is someone who will implement very strict timelines in order to get things done. I had trouble keeping up because I wasn't used to having such deadlines, but she would just tell me to be faster next time and move on.//Recently, she put up a huge whiteboard at her desk which detailed all her meetings and tasks for the month. I was very impressed with the set-up, and asked her what the tasks on her board meant. She became very irritated when I asked if there was room for one more teammate, and she finally snapped and said 'not everything with my name needs you involved.'//I was surprised at her hostility, but just thought she was having a bad day. But ever since then, she's been very distant and just generally difficult to work with. She wouldn't be as helpful as before when it came to retrieving documents that I need, implemented tougher deadlines, and would just avoid me by going home earlier.//I felt that she was creating an overly hostile work environment that was affecting my productivity, and felt like the right thing to do was to report her to HR. I did so, after collecting some evidence, and HR said that they would talk to her. Well, the talk didn't seem to go well because now our boss has told me to just stay out of her way, and removed me from all projects that involves her. Thea has even been moved to another section in the office, closer to our seniors, who I've heard been trying to placate her to stop her from leaving.//I'm conflicted as I don't want to ruin my workplace relationships. But it was very difficult to work with her, and I did what I thought was the right thing to advocate for myself. AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for letting my pregnant coworker get in trouble?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="ignoring or neglecting duties or people" intention="conforming to norms" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>Throwaway account, I'll try to keep it all as brief as possible. English isn't my first language so I apologise if there's any mistakes.//I, (f24), work an office job.//I have a co-worker, Anne (f28). Anne is currently pregnant, and is around 6 months pregnant.//We have a dedicated break room where we go for lunch, as we aren't allowed to eat anything or drink anything except water bottles in the office because of the computers.//We all have our own break schedules that are the same everyday. Anne and I go to break together, our lunch break is from 13:30 to 14:30. No one else is on this schedule, and take their breaks earlier or later.//In the break room, there's a few chairs and a couple of couches.//Over the past two weeks, Anne had started taking naps on one of the couches during her lunch break. I know it's not my business as to what she does on her break, she can do what she wants.//Last Friday, Anne and I were taking our breaks as usual. I was listening to music on my headphones, and when it was around 14:30, I got up to go back to work. I didn't really pay attention to what Anne was doing.//Everyone was confused and was saying &quot;where's Anne?&quot; by around 15:00 because they needed her, and our boss went into the break room and Anne was still sleeping. Anne got a warning from our boss.//Anne is now angry with me, because our breaks end at the same time so I should have woken her up. She said I'm selfish and careless. A lot of our other coworkers are on Anne's side and agree.//I told Anne if she can't wake up, she shouldn't sleep during her break. She said the baby makes her tired and accused me of calling her lazy and being insensitive.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling my colleague that her Deaf assistant's emails have terrible grammar and are making our company look unprofessional?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="telling the truth" intention="exercising authority" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I work for a company owned by my mother, a small company in that provides professional services where it's expected that all written communication be written in proper, formal English. My mother has also been ill for the majority of the pandemic (but not with COVID) and I have stepped in to run most of the company while she recovers.//We've all been working from home for an entire year, and one of our employees has decided to move out of our city and buy a large house in the suburbs to work from home, which is fine. But since she's working from home and raising her kids, she's hired a local college student as an assistant, which was smart thinking on her part as far as I'm concerned.//Except her assistant is capital D Deaf. I was a little skeptical at first, because we get lots of business phone calls in our line of work and I figured an assistant would be answering the phone, but I don't know what jobs her assistant would be doing in her stead and didn't want to go into things with a preconceived notion of her assistant's abilities.//But dear god is this woman's grammar atrocious. It doesn't matter if she's sending an email from her own account or from her boss' account, they look and read as if written by a child. Her assistant has only been working with us for a few weeks but I've already had to have two conversations with the employee about insisting her assistant proofreads emails before they're sent. I was told that &quot;English is her second language&quot; (ASL being her first), and that Deaf people &quot;don't understand grammar like we do&quot;. I told her that was a cop-out, as two of our other high-ranking employees speak English as their second language and have no problem typing like professional adults while also juggling their lives and families. During a phone call I said something like &quot;She's Deaf, not blind, make her read a copy of Strunk and White or fire her&quot;.//Today my mother received an email from the employee (and we can tell because it's actually legible!) complaining about me not making accommodations for her handicapped assistant and she says that I was being too harsh. Was I the asshole in holding a Deaf woman to the same communication standards as everyone else in our company?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling my coworker to take her gloves off?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="lower" relationship="same" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="yes" action="making or declining requests" intention="following rules" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>Me (15M) have been working in a bakery for about 6 months, I stared to notice that my coworker (16F) that has been working for about 9 months was wearing gloves. Where I work we have single use tissue paper that we use for each item, we pick it up then throw the tissues away. This works great and ensure food is save for costumers. But my coworker at the start of her shift puts gloves on and does everything with them, she touches money, packs bread touches the POS system, then touches the breads and other items with theses contaminated gloves and doesn’t use the tissues. Nobody is allowed to do this at my work, but no one seems to call her out for this people see her do it and want to say something but don’t, as she was serving this guy he hands her cash she uses her gloves to touch the money and get change, she then comes over to the table and starts to pack cheese and bacon rolls with theses gloves she has been wearing for 4 hours and just touched money with. As i saw this I lost it in my head thinking what the fuck is wrong with her! I nicely say “ hey not trying to be mean or anything but we can’t be using gloves that you just touched money with and then go and pack that is so dirty and gross”. She rolled her eyes and just stopped and looked at me angry because I just called her out. She then says to me “ firstly don’t tell me what to do I’ve been working her for longer and secondly I never touched money with theses gloves” I responded “ I literally just say you serve that man and take money from him” she replies with “ okay fine mabye I did I’ll go and change them if it’s such a big deal” rolling her eye as she changed her gloves. She then puts new gloves on and does the same thing touches bread, money and doesn’t change the gloves. At this point I’m losing it . As I am the only boy who works in sales most of my coworkers have no issue with me. When I went into my next shift the following week this girls sister and some of my other coworkers completely ingore me and one of my coworkers let me know that this girl with the gloves told everyone that I was screaming at her and telling her that she shouldn’t be using gloves. Now most people hate me because of this girl at my work and she is making it all up. So I’m wondering who is the asshole?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for not giving my pregnant employee maternity leave?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="cheating or violating company rules" intention="exercising authority" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Sorry this might be long but requires some explanation. Throwaway so ppl don't recognize me.//I own a small-ish business. Our employees are all full-time salaried employees and are paid once per month. We give everyone 30 days of PTO every year that can be used at any time, for any reason. It just has to be approved beforehand so that operations aren't disrupted. It never expires and accrues indefinitely at 2.5 days per month.//We also give everyone what we refer as &quot;hiatus&quot;. This is just like PTO but is accrues more slowly. It's 60 days every 4 years - accrues at 1.25 days per month. However, employees cannot use this until they accrue at least 30 days. So they must wait 2 years at least between each hiatus.//So as long as someone doesn't take any unpaid time off, they could take a month off every year and then another 2 months off every 4 years. Hiatus and PTO can be combined into 3 full months off - if the employee chooses to do that. We do not offer maternity leave or any other type of leave. However, in practice, most people use hiatus as a form of maternity leave. We do allow employees to go into negative PTO for life and death situations if their balance is 0 - but there are limits to this.//We do all of this to keep things fair. I don't think that people should be punished for having a baby but I also don't think that people should have to endure more work and pickup the slack for their coworkers without getting anything in return. I think the system we have is extremely generous and fair.//One of our employees, &quot;Jen&quot; is accusing us of discrimination. She is unexpectedly pregnant and wants to take time off. She has used all of her time so far and wants to either go negative for a month or two, or be given additional PTO. My answer was &quot;no&quot; but I offered her a few months of unpaid time off.//She didn't take this well and is making some dramatic statements that are causing a bit of a disruption at the office. At this point it's becoming a problem. My partner is very sympathetic and wants to be accommodating but I'm sort of taking a hard line here. Especially since this hasn't ever been a problem before. AITA?//Edit: we are not bound by any government mandate to offer leave. Jen has been our employee for 4 years. We have 47 employees.//Edit 2: any employee is able to work from home as long as they work a minimum of 40 hours per week. As long as they meet their deadlines and attend all meetings, they can make their own schedules.//Edit 3: We offer short term and long term disability insurance but it's optional. Most people choose not to take advantage of these benefits because, while we cover a portion of the cost, it's still &quot;expensive&quot; depending on the options you select//Edit 4: Conclusion: most people expect the owners of businesses to subsidize their decision to have children. Equal benefits for all employees isn't equal at all because parents should get extra leave and special treatment as a standard. If someone decides not to have children, they need to be paid less. Reading all of your comments was very interesting. Thank you!</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for embarrassing an employee?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="seeking fairness or justice" impact="damage to reputation" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>My company has a training website that we use. Think companyname.trainingwebsite.com. Employees are required to log in to this website with a username and password to complete this training. If you go directly to that site all you need is your username and password. If, however, you go to trainingwebsite.com you have to log in with an organization code.//As I get at least ten calls a week from people asking me for their login information (For some I just forward the same exact email I sent them last time with the same exact attachment) giving them the company code will just cause confusion and encourage more idiotic phone calls to me.//Last week an employee called me up insisting that she needed the code and that the website on her login sheet was requiring it. I instructed her to type the link into the address bar which she insisted she had done. I asked if she had typed the link into Google or if she had clicked on it, as typing the link into Google will bring up the main website. She insisted she clicked on it. I went to the website and logged in as her with no code and told her it was fine. Boomers tend to type web addresses into Google search, I have no idea why.//Well she went to her supervisor in tears that the website was broken and I refused to help her. The vice president of the company pulled me into a conference room, ripped into me, and ordered me to give everyone the code. I tried to explain she wasn't following simple instructions but he kept cutting me off saying that my instructions were wrong.//I saw red. I found the employee and ordered her to come with me, I brought her to the conference room, handed her login sheet to her, and instructed her to log in on the presentation monitor. She began pulling up Google. I ordered her to stop, reminding her that she had insisted she didn't type it in Google.//She said that's how you go to a website. I shook my head, &quot;No, it isn't! You swore you didn't go to Google so if you are not a liar, show me where the website required that code.&quot;//Her supervisor told her to type it in the address bar, and when she did, surprise surprise, no code required. She insisted that it had required it before.//I said, &quot;No, it did not. You lied to me, you lied to your supervisor, and you wasted everyone's time today. Next time just admit you can't follow directions.&quot;//The supervisor thinks I should have handled it one on one and I was TA for embarrassing her. The VP agrees with me and thinks that she needed to be ready to back up her complaint. The employee keeps insisting she's not a liar and I went out of my way to insult her.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA For making the only woman at our job quit?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="personal vendetta" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>This occurred over the course of months and I was recently telling my family about this story and my sister got mad at me and called me a sexist, but none of my actions had anything to do with that://I work at a small client service office, it only has about 50 people, all male (with the exception of a few support staff that were women). At the beginning of 2019 we had a new hire to our professional team who was a female. She initially fit right in at the beginning, but slowly she started to make changes and change our workplace for the worse://Prior to her joining, we had a very relaxed atmosphere. We'd curse, talk more explicitly, etc. No one seemed to mind, even our direct managers didn't care. But she complained about foul language and behavior and soon our HR person got involved and told us we had to keep it more professional. Additionally, she was catty and would report people every so often.//Essentially she was making the workplace sterile and boring. We couldn't &quot;let loose&quot; as much and all conversations had to be workplace appropriate.//Our team would even have our own little events like going out drinking together afterwards/go to concerts together, and obviously we excluded her, which she got wind of and, obviously reported it. So now we weren't allowed to hang out as a team unless all were invited after work.//I eventually told our team to not help her out with any projects and give her the bare minimum of assistance if she needed it. Most of the team agreed and within a few months time her performance dropped. I also made sure to report her every time she inconvenienced me.//She eventually had a mini-breakdown and ended up quitting. Obviously at work the immediate team celebrated but my sister apparently thought it was sexist? I told her if this had been a male doing it, we would have excluded him too.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for firing a female employee who posts provocative underwear pictures on her Instagram?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="violating professional boundaries" intention="exercising authority" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I (m29) run a successful event planning business that I started with my ex wife about 7 years ago. When my ex wife and I divorced, she also divorced the business, and I then employed about 9 people to work for me. We now have offices and we have a tight group of employees who are almost like family to me now.//About 6 months ago one of my employees told me she was pregnant, and as a result was going to leave the business to be a full time stay at home mom. I had no issue with this, but it meant I had to find a new employee to take her place. I interviewed a lot of people before finding Olivia, who I went on to employ.//Olivia has lots of experience and is absolutely fantastic at her job. The clients love her and she’s really in tune with what the clients needs and desires are. The nature of our work is to build a rapport with our clients, which sometimes means social media is added by clients.//For my other employees this has never been an issue. They post respectable pictures of their families or travelling, it’s never been a cause for concern. Olivia, on the other hand, thinks herself as a bit of an amateur underwear model, and posts these pictures on her Instagram in very provocative poses. Usually I wouldn’t have an issue with this, but I don’t want clients seeing them and immediately looking down on my business.//I have Olivia a warning about a month after she started working for me and told her to stop posting pictures like that as it was bad for the image of the company. She said okay and for a while she did, but then after a month she started posting them again, even more than she did before. When quarantine began we were extremely busy as a lot of clients were calling worried their events were going to be cancelled, and during this time Olivia was posting a provocative picture once every few days.//Out of pure stress I fired her and told her I didn’t want her to work for me anymore, and she said she was going to sue me for “discrimination” and claimed I was being sexist which I definitely wasn’t. The rest of my employees are threatening to leave in solidarity with Olivia. AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling my co-worker that kids isn't an excuse, she needs to do her damn job?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="same" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="making or declining requests" intention="conforming to norms" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Background: I have about 14 colleagues and a boss. Of the 16 of us, only 3 of them do not have children. I am one of the ones that do, I have 3 of them. I'm also a single mom.//The issue: One of my co-workers with a kid, definitely plays the mom card. I usually hate using that term as shit comes up when you have kids. But she uses this as to why she can never come in on time, why she needs to leave early, why she’s always so preoccupied with her phone, why she can’t focus on what she’s doing so then she screws up and we have to fix her mistakes, etc. Her kid is 9 years old, in school all day (not even doing virtual learning, but in school). He’s a neurotypical kid, with no health issues. I get worrying about him, but like I said, about 80% of us have kids. We all still show up and do our job. And honestly, the excuse of “I have a kid” wears thin, especially about coming in early and late because her husband doesn’t work, so he can take care of their son. Our boss defends her and refuses to do anything about her negligence. I do blame our boss more because she just allows it to happen. But I do think my co-worker needs to step up while we’re at work. I have tried talking to her, nicely, she says she’ll do better and never does. I’ve asked if she needs help with something, offering support and she says she’s fine. I also went to HR and they did diddly squat except have a meeting telling us we all need to pull our weight. Nothing changed.//The other day, she screwed up again. She was on her phone like she is most of the day and wasn’t giving it her all. It was a huge mistake that nearly cost us a client and it’s one that she’s made several times before. I admit, I wasn’t nice with her about this. I didn’t yell, but my tone was clipped and I told her that she needs to put the damn phone away and actually pay attention to what she’s doing. She got in a tizzy, saying that she was texting her husband about their son and she didn’t mean to, she’s sorry, etc. I said it wasn’t okay and she needs to just focus. She then tried saying “I have a kid, my mind is in two places”. I told her “I have 3 kids, that all go to different schools. I am here every morning on time, I stay until it’s time to go. I may have to take a call for my kids occasionally, I get you think about kids all the time, but I also manage to do my job. This excuse just doesn’t fly anymore. Do your damn job.” She quickly went about fixing her mistake and I walked away.//She didn’t go to HR or our boss over it, but someone else who overheard it did. I was severely reprimanded for this, saying that it’s not my job to have that talk with her. I said maybe not, but the people who’s job it was, weren’t doing anything. I didn’t get a formal write up, but things are tense.//Some of my co-workers think I did the right thing, others think I should’ve documented it with HR and let it go. I’m torn. AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling a new colleague it’s her problem she lied about her qualifications and she can see for herself how to get by?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="creative" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="exercising authority" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I (26) make up the 3D modeling department of my company. The workload has gotten too much for me to handle on my own, so I asked for a second person. The company provided me with a girl (22) who graduated this year from the same college I went to. This college offers a 3 semester 3D course, of which only the first one is required, rest is optional, but she told me she’d taken all three. Her portfolio looks decent as well.//To keep this short, everything she produced was messed up and borderline unusable, causing me to spend a lot of time just fixing all her mistakes. She was also extremely slow, slower than I expected. This confused me, because with her supposed experience, the stuff I gave her to do shouldn’t have been such a struggle. On top of that I always said she could come to me if she gets stuck on something, but she never did.//I asked her why all her meshes are so bad and why she didn’t come to me for help, and she confessed. She’d only taken the required semester, her average was a D because the meshes were horrible and she hoped she could fake it for a while. I told her that is just not acceptable and that I have no use for her here. (FYI: Calling her meshes bad wasn't me just being rude. They can be objectively bad/messed up when it comes to functionality and usability. I said her meshes were ugly, then that would've been rude.)//She then told me that she was obviously desperate or she wouldn’t have taken a job she could barely do. She begged me to teach her to get her to where she’s supposed to be, but I was having none of it. I wanted someone to help with all the work I already had, not someone I’d have to teach almost from the ground up. If I teach her during working hours, I’ll be even more behind on my own work and I sure as hell don’t feel like using my free time for this. My central problem with this situation is that this is not something you get good at in a few weeks, especially in terms of efficiency and speed, which is why I was happy about her having taken all 3 semesters.//I told her she knew she was under qualified, so she can find out how to get up to speed by herself. Watch some tutorials, do some exercises at home. At work I’ll help her, but only to an extent, or else I could just do it myself in the first place. But when the boss asks me why I’m now slower than before, I won’t lie. This has obviously caused a rift in our work-relationship.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for telling an employee she can choose between demotion or termination?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="yes" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="exercising authority" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I own a vape shop. We're a small business, only 12 employees.//One of my employees, Peggy, was supposed to open yesterday. Peggy has recently been promoted to Manager, after 2 solid years of good work as a cashier. I really thought she could handle the responsibility.//So, I wake up, 3 hours after the place should be open, and I have 22 notifications on the store Facebook page. Customers have been trying to come shop, but the store is closed. Employees are showing up to work, but they're locked out.//I call Peggy, and get no response. I text her, same thing. So I go in and open the store. An hour before her shift was supposed to be over, she calls me back.//I ask her if she's ok, and she says she needed to &quot;take a mental health day and do some self-care&quot;. I'm still pretty pissed at this point, but I'm trying to be understanding, as I know how important mental health can be. So I ask her why she didn't call me as soon as she knew she needed the day off. Her response: &quot;I didn't have enough spoons in my drawer for that.&quot;.//Frankly, IDK what that means. But it seems to me like she's saying she cannot be trusted to handle the responsibility of opening the store in the AM.//So I told her that she had two choices://Go back to her old position, with her old pay.//I fire her completely.//She's calling me all sorts of &quot;-ist&quot; now, and says I'm discriminating against her due to her poor mental health and her gender.//None of this would have been a problem if she simply took 2 minutes to call out. I would have got up and opened the store on time. But this no-call/no-show shit is not the way to run a successful business.//I think I might be the AH here, because I am taking away her promotion over something she really had no control over.//But at the same time, she really could have called me.//So, reddit, I leave it to you: Am I the asshole?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for my “discriminatory” instructions to my elderly employee?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="safety concerns" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>Obligatory throwaway notice//I know the title seems absurd, but hear me out.//I (27f) am the head of a childcare-related business. We’re relatively small (only about six employees) but the ones I’ll be mentioning are K (17f) and B (86f).//B, though in excellent shape, is elderly and isn’t able to move around as well as she once did. She often plays with the kids and allows them to be physical with her. We employ her as an as-needed worker, meaning she generally comes later in the day when K is working.//A few weeks ago, B was playing with the children and allowed them to get rough with her (pull on her clothes, push her around, etc). K tried to intervene, but B assured her it was all fine and that she could take care of herself.//Well, later that day, one of the children hugged her so hard that she tripped and fell into the wooden playhouse. She ended up being virtually incapacitated on the ground. Meaning K, the seventeen year old, had to call 911 and help B as best she could, all while having to wrangle over a dozen young children. B ended up being totally fine, and was released from the hospital the next day.//However, that event was extremely hard on K. She’s an extremely capable worker, but seeing someone she cared about hurt combined with having to call 911 and being virtually alone with the kids was hard. She asked me privately if I would be okay with instructing B and the kids to not get too physical with B. K has said she’s terrified of having another event like that, and I don’t blame her.//I talked with the kids and parents to make sure they understand that playing with K is different than playing with B, and they need to be more gentle. However, when I discussed this with B, she accused me of being ageist and said she could do everything she used to do just fine. Our coworkers are divided. AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for replying to a coworkers inappropriate texts by work email, and attaching them?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>One of my coworkers who I had thought was friendly but that was it (he is married) sent me some inappropriate texts at like 3 am on St. Patricks Day weekend.//Asking me to come over and &quot;have some fun&quot; and saying that he had been into me for a while and knew I felt the same. (I don't, I'm a lesbian but not out at work)//He also sent me a naked selfie that (luckily) cut off right before his dick but ... Dang it was close.//When I saw them, I was out with friends and was like &quot;What the fuck... Ok this is a Monday problem&quot;. I have a really strict rule with myself that I don't do work, think about work, or answer messages about work outside of 9-5 M-F. I also don't use my personal phone for work stuff. If someone from work calls or texts and it's not one of the coworkers I see as a close friend and trust to not talk shop on the weekends, I'm not answering...//And I included dealing with this fucker as a &quot;workday problem&quot; so I ignored his message. He sent me several later first saying sorry he was drunk. Then saying he hadn't said it how he wanted to but he was still into me and had a feeling I felt the same.//On Monday, I wrote him an email on the work email saying://&quot;Hi 'Coworker'//I'm writing to follow up on your messages from the prior several days (See attached)//Please only contact me through work channels during regular business hours, I do not use my personal number with colleagues.//Additionally, I found the content of your messages unwelcome and inappropriate. Please only contact me regarding work.//OP&quot;I didn't send the email to HR but I did blind CC my personal email so I'd have a copy just in case.//And he got really mad, he texted me back saying I had crossed a line attaching his picture to a work email, was I trying to get him fired?//I screenshot that text too and attached it to an additional email saying &quot;As per my prior email, please only contact me about work matters, and only on my business email or Slack.&quot;//He stopped texting me but he came to my desk to speak to me and before he said anything I asked &quot;Is this a work question?&quot; And he said I knew what it was about, and I said that I wasn't available for a discussion at the moment, if he did need to meet with me for a work matter, could he please schedule a meeting on the calendar and include a readahead to brief me on the topic of the meeting?//He walked off...//I feel like I was a bit of a bitch in dealing with it when maybe I could have told him to cut it out by text. But I'm also fucking sick of dealing with this shit at every job, and I feel like my patience to use my own time and energy to gently ask guys to cool it is worn thin. And I want to set the precident that I won't engage at all, outside of work hours or work accounts.//AITA for sending that email?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for Not Paying My Employee for Her Sick Days" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="following rules" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I (50f) am a director at an arts nonprofit and have one direct report (25f) underneath me. Our fiscal year starts in July, and she has taken 13 of her 15 vacation days already.//She recently requested an additional 7 days off to go on a trip in June. When I asked her about it, she said she would use her unused sick days as PTO.//As a company, we get 15 vacation days, 9 sick days, and 3 personal days. I told her that sick days are not to be used the same as PTO, they are only to be used when sick. She pushed back, saying employees should be able to use all of their allotted days off for any reason, otherwise she was being ‘punished’ for not being sick and not taking those sick days off throughout the year.//I ultimately decided to not pay her for her upcoming vacation, because I don’t want to start a new precedent for the whole company to use sick days and PTO interchangeably.//Here is where I’m wondering if I’m TAH. When I told her she would not be paid, she asked if she were to be sick for the same amount of time before the end of the year, would I pay her then? I answered yes, because if she is genuinely sick, we owe her that time off. Sick days do not roll over at the end of the year, but I held firm that sick days are only to be used when genuinely sick.//So Reddit, AITA for not letting my employee use unused sick days as PTO?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for telling my colleague he only has his job because his uncle is the CEO?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="personal vendetta" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I’m early 20sF and last year started working at a major company. I entered this job through a scheme for disadvantaged young people. Despite this, the interview process was still incredibly tough and I’m proud to have made it this far.//When I’m not with my team I hang out with the other girls I’ve met and befriended through that scheme. The nephew of the CEO started his role at our department a little later and for whatever reason has been joining us girls for lunches etc. He tries VERY HARD to fit in and acts like he doesn’t come from a place of insane privilege. He will literally pretend to be humble and downplay his family’s wealth just to seem relatable I guess.//The others have been warming up to him but I’m honestly not buying his rather fake personality.//The other day I was sitting at the canteen with another coworker and he asked if he could join us. I didn’t want that but my coworker immediately said yes.//Well he was asking me lots of personal questions and about my journey to the company. I told him that the interview process was hard and mentally draining. He nodded and said that it’s tough getting into the place but that his interviews were “fine”. Even laughing and saying he came late to one because of a hungover.//This made me mad and I said “good for you”. He thanked me and said that things always work out when you just “chill out” and stop taking things so seriously. This is when I said that we both know he’s not nearly as competent as he believes and that he only got the job bc his uncle is literally the CEO.//My friend/coworker gasped and looked at me like I’m crazy. The nephew shrugged and said that I don’t seem to like him. I told him that this wasn’t a personal matter so likes and dislikes are irrelevant.//We didn’t argue but he got a little heated. And asking me what I want him to do. Then he said that I may view him as an over privileged asshole but I’m more or less the same (which makes no sense).//So I fully expected him to report me to HR but to my surprise he never did. In fact he started following me on my social media accounts and messaging me at work more frequently.//My coworker has relayed this incident to the other girls and the consensus is that I’m a major asshole. They said that not only was I unnecessarily hostile and rude, they’re also mad he started hanging out with them less. (Not sure if this is a coincidence but I’ve also been spending less time with them)//AITA for giving my unprompted opinions?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA to tell a coworker to shut up about her weight ?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="retaliation" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I (29 f) work for a small company. We recently got two a new employee in my department C(20F). I don't know her very well, because I mostly work only from home. The first day I saw them was actually on the day we celebrated my birthday at work. I cut the cake in multiple smalls servings so everybody can enjoy and C said &quot;I shouldn't, I'm watching my weight&quot;.//The thing is, I am obese 300lbs for 5'8. I don't have a complex regarding my weight and I am healthy, but I try my best everyday to lose weight since I want to start a family. I do have multiples medical difficulties regarding losing weight, PCOS being the main one. And C, she is probably three times thinner than me. I brushed it off, thinking she just was just making an excuse for not wanting cake.//The week after, as I came in the office, I heard her saying &quot;but guys, I am morbidly obese&quot;. Thinking it was a coincidence, I laughed and said &quot;If you are, what am I ?&quot; before getting to my desk. She continued talking about being &quot;fat&quot;, despite everybody telling her to change the subject, even told her to calculate her BMI and stop if it doesn't say &quot;morbidly obese&quot;. Which she did, but denied having a heathy weight despite the calculator saying so.//The day after, I came in early with a coworker R(28M). She sat next to him after greeting us. Before anybody asked or said anything, she quickly told him 'By the way, I'm starting intermittent fasting&quot;. He asked why and then C explained that her doctor told her yesterday (even though she worked all day?) that &quot;she has PCOS and if she doesn't lose weight, she will become diabetic&quot;.//I couldn't help but laughed. I know this is bullshit. She might have PCOS, but there is multiple steps before getting to this point. R tried to make her stop, but she continued, so I lost it and just told her to &quot;shut up about her weight&quot;, since I was getting really annoyed. She didn't said a word to me all day after that.//It has been two days and I don't feel too good about it. R told me I am not the blame per se, but I could have been nicer. My coworkers say that she deserved it since she was told multiple times to change the subject. So yea, AITA ?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA [25F] for refusing to work weekends (and assume extra responsibilities) because my manager’s boss had a baby?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="nan" relationship="inferior" industry="professional" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="productivity decrease" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>I received a 1.5% salary increase (a slap in the face), which will be effective in April, even though I’ve been labeled a star performer.//My manager’s boss’s wife recently had a baby, and because my manager wants to get promoted, she’s taken on a lot of his responsibilities. She’s hired a new guy who has a higher title than me (and works a strict 9-5) so I thought she’d ask him to work weekends. Unfortunately, it doesn’t seem like he wants to work more than he’s supposed to.//I’ve been asked to work weekends in order to be a team player and be understanding because her boss recently had a baby. She said that “it’ll get better”. AITA for not caring if her boss has one baby or twenty? I’m not interested in doing my boss’s work or her boss’s work without getting compensated accordingly.//EDIT: I don’t work for a large firm. My work experience is NOT valuable. If I worked at a larger firm with more opportunities for cultivating valuable work experience that’ll set me up for years to come, I’d be more than happy to work the weekends.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for refusing to be on time to work until my boss talks to me about it?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="M" experience="higher" relationship="inferior" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="yes" action="cheating or violating company rules" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>I work in fast food. I've had this job 6 years, and I've always struggled to be on time. A few months in, I was made a manager. There always needs to be a manager in the building, but at that location, it made no difference if I was late- there were always multiple managers there.//And then I was transferred to my current location. It's smaller, and has a lot less managers. If I was late, someone would be waiting for me to show up so they could leave. After about a week, I sat down with my manager, Eliza, and we made a deal. My schedule was changed so that all of my shifts started an hour earlier. So I had 9 hour shifts, instead of 8, and there was a guaranteed one hour overlap between me and the person before me. And it worked wonderfully. Even being regularly late, I still had the smoothest transitions because of that overlap, and nobody was inconvenienced. The manager before me would also sometimes be able to leave early, which everyone (in particular, Eliza, who was salaried) enjoyed. Eliza even tried to convince the others working my shift to do that as well, but they refused. So it's still an 8 hour shift, with only me working 9 hours.//2 months ago, Eliza got transferred. We got a new manager, John. I don't know how the transition goes, but I assumed that even if he was made aware of it, he would not be willing to continue my deal from before. I've had a second job now for 3 months, and easily worked through my lateness issues there (tardiness isn't punished there, but makes the job much more difficult- the work starts on time, whether you're there or not), and felt like I could do fine with that at my main job as well, as long as we could go back to the 8 hour shifts. But when we got our first schedule made by John, I was still given a longer shift, with an hour earlier start time. I honestly prefer it this way- mostly because it allows me to stress a lot less about when I get there. John seems to like it that way too- he regularly leaves early on my days. So I see no need to bring it up with him. But I'm being told by the other managers (and even some crew) that John complains constantly to them about my lateness.//Am I the asshole for not being on time until my manager addresses it with me?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for commenting about my colleague's acne?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="same" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="retaliation" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>Some background: I'd like to think that I'm fit. I was an athletic girl growing up. As an adult, I work out and watch I eat. People would not describe me as skinny - I'm more muscular because I do heavy weightlifting.//People at work know that I go to the gym but they don't know that I lift and that I'm trying to build muscle on purpose. They assume I have this certain lifestyle because I'm trying to lose weight.//This happened last week, and my friends and colleagues have mixed opinions so now I'm posting it here.//I have a colleague Nina (fake name), and she has a really bad acne problem. She also likes to make unsolicited and sometimes snide remarks about people. Most of our other colleagues just ignore her because they don't want office drama. I'm generally a quiet person. I keep to myself but if someone is rude to me, I usually have a comeback. Although this rarely happens at work because most people let me be.//So one day at lunch, I was eating with my friends in the office cafeteria. Since I eat healthily, I prefer to bring my own lunches to work. I always eat red rice instead of regular rice and no one really cares about what I eat. While eating, Nina decided to join us at our table so we let her.//Nina saw my lunch and made a face. Then commented, &quot;I don't understand how you're always eating red rice which is supposed to help you lose weight, but you're still fat. It's a waste of money, to be honest.&quot; Red rice is more expensive than white rice, btw.//To which I laughed and replied, &quot;Oh, you mean like you and your dermatologist? I can imagine you pay them a lot but your acne doesn't seem to be going away.&quot;//She then called me a b*tch, got up, and walked out.//Some of my friends were on my side because she started it. While some were saying I'm an AH because my weight doesn't really bother me, but her acne bothers her a lot.//So AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for reporting my coworker to HR after she kept on trying to reconcile with me?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="same" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="No" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I work in an office building where I am pretty much at odds with everyone else. I understand why. In fact, I'm a loner with bad hair due to stress and fatigue at 25 and slightly overweight after dealing with depression for many years due to the death of my father and my two brothers which I've started to get over.//Jan 2020, I got a job in an office setting. Unfortunately, in spite of the pandemic, I've been on mandatory in person shifts for months now. When I started, I tried my best to gel with everyone and make friends but pretty much everyone rejected me. Called me names as I worked behind the desk from their little cliques. Ignored me when I approached them. Some even blatantly insulted me for my hair and weight when I didn't even bring it up. This was from everyone, even guys who I thought would be more accepting than the women were mean as fuck to me too.//There was one woman, J, who is about the same age as me, who was different though from everyone else. I really thought that this one woman who acted so kind and genuine towards me (and who I liked as more than just a friend back then) was my only &quot;friend&quot; there. I mean, she was inviting me to hang out with her alone after work. I bought her drinks, we talked and texted regularly after work for several months.//A few months into our friendship, I was added into a group chat where I saw she was shit talking me about secrets I confided in her - mainly insecurities about my height and my physical attributes such as my hair and weight. All these worries about my future. All my fears. I told them all to her and she exposed me really quite hard. That did hurt. It broke my heart actually. But from then on, I understood never to trust anybody at that division and ignored her when she approached me, and she figured out that I had caught on to her exposing what I told her privately to her friends. From then on, we never talked to each other outside of work matters.//I thought that would be that. I would avoid everyone outside of work matters. But nope. Very recently, J approached me soaked in tears after work. She told me that she missed my company and wanted me to be there for her after one of the people in her friend group &quot;treated her like trash&quot;. I figured it was some drama with regards to her love life and told her that no, I don't want to and never want to speak to her. She persisted, again and again and again. Approaching me at work to start inane convos, texting me after it and so on.//It was getting irritating and I snapped at her one day to leave me alone, calling her a &quot;stupid-ass bitch&quot;. I admit, a mean insult. But I just don't like her and I don't want to speak to her. She just bawled and left me alone for a bit. But she started up harassing me in person and from text again, and I've had to talk to HR to stop her harassment. J was placed in a separate part of our division and sent me an angry stream of texts lambasting me as a &quot;prick&quot;. Am I the asshole for reporting her like that?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for asking my handicapped coworker not to touch my belongings?" op_gender="F" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>I work(ed) at a grocery store and I was fired yesterday for asking my autistic coworker to stop touching my things.//I’m a 19f and I work at a store that employs a few people with mental disabilities. I’ve of course never had an issue with any of them, they’re all very nice people. It’s very easy to accommodate for them working a little slower and most of them do a great job.//There’s this one man I work with that has a pretty severe mental handicap. I’ve had a couple conversations with him and he seems like a sweet and cool guy, it’s just he has a habit of touching other peoples stuff.//We have lockers and since I don’t have a lock and people never steal at my job, I just put my bag in the locker and shut it before I go to work. Well a couple nights ago I caught him holding my bag and going through my things. Just sort of touching them and laying them on the table. (NO DAMAGE)//I asked him really nice not to touch my things. Like super super nice. Like, “hey could you do me a favor and not go through my things? thank you” with a smile. Well a day passes, I come into work, and the same thing happens. I took all of my things out of his hands and put them into my bag gently and said, “I asked you once remember? So please don’t touch my things.” He just sort of whined and looked really bad but also kind of angry. So I decide to bring it up with my supervisor because it bothers me.//I was then pulled into the managers office a couple hours into work and he told me that I was being disrespectful. Apparently the coworker that was touching my stuff told them that I was really mean to him about it and that I threatened him?! I was so confused. I asked if they had cameras in the break room but they don’t for privacy reasons. But they would’ve been helpful in this scenario.//I’m not sure why he lied about my behavior but it got me fired. It could be that’s how he interpreted it. Now his mom is pissed at me and the managers. I also heard from my friend that I work with that some of our coworkers were gossiping about me and saying rude things about me.//I’m worried that he told them that because of how I came off. I could’ve seemed condescending or mean but I really was trying to be patient and nice. I feel pretty bad but also mad that I lost my job over this.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for reporting a coworker to a supervisor?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="same" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="following rules" impact="emotional distress" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>So this coworker and I started at the same time a few weeks ago, but she is very young. She is 25 and I am 41. She looks a lot younger than she is and sometimes the supervisor gets on her for things that aren't really a huge issue, but I think she is talking town to her because she looks like she is a teenager. I told her that she should dress older, which she did and the boss started talking down to her less. Anyways, yesterday she was supposed to print out a memo she had written and she accidentally misgendered a client in the memo (who is trans). She caught this typo shortly after printing out the memo and putting it in everyone's box. She panicked, ran down to the mailroom and frantically pulled all the memos and then reprinted the memos and replaced them in everyone's box. Instead of just telling the boss, she did all this because this lady is exceptionally hard on her and she was afraid she might lose her job for this small mistake. The only person who had taken the original memo out of the box was another young girl and she ran to this girls cubicle, asked her for the memo and replaced it with a new one and asked her not to tell the boss, which this girl promised not to. At lunch she went to staples and bought paper to replace the paper from the memo so the boss wouldn't catch all the missing paper. I thought it was kind of dishonest, so I told the boss what happened. The boss reprimanded her in the meeting in front of everyone and this girl started crying and left the office for the day. The other girl who know the problem came up to me after the meeting and told me I was an asshole for reporting her to the boss, and said the typo was not a big deal and she said I should have known the boss would have an unreasonable response and that this girl was just trying to save herself from this issue. Am I the asshole?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for telling my Coworker there are no work emergencies so I can play with my dog?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="M" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="ignoring or neglecting duties or people" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="productivity decrease" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>This has come up a couple of times now and I don't think I'm the asshole but I wanted a second opinion.//I've been working at my job for about 5 years now and currently I am working from home full time. Because of this I get to hang out with my wife and our dog for most of the day. I normally take a 5-10 minute break around 4 or 5 times throughout the day so I can play with my dog. When I do that if I get a work message I just let people know I'll be a couple minutes and then I'll get back to them. I've been doing that almost every day for the past couple years and it hasn't been an issue until recently.//My coworker Mark occasionally asks for files or needs me to review something and if he reaches out during our playtime I tell him the same thing as everyone else. However he's started to complain that I am doing this.//The most recent one was he asked me to review some work for a project that he claimed was urgent and needed it done immediately. However my review is the third to last step for the project and the final two steps are also quick to do. The project also did not need to be completed until the 20th. I told him that I was in the middle of fetch but I would review and sign off on it in 30 minutes. He then pushed and said it was an emergency and it needed to be done now. I told him we don't really have work emergencies and we'll finish the project today but there's still 2 weeks until it's due.//For reference I've been working here for almost 5 years now and Mark is close to a year here, and I am the senior most member on our team so I know our processes pretty well. I haven't had any complaints from other people about this and my work is always done on time, so I don't think it should be an issue for anyone else if I spend some time with my dog. But he continues to complain that I was slowing him down and should've done it right away like he asked. AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for nearly getting my colleague fired and then refusing to help him?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="nan" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="seeking fairness or justice" impact="disruption to workplace dynnamics" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>So I am 26, have been in my company for 3 years, I am in sales and the colleague in this case let's call him J is in customer support.//Everything was going good but problems started around last year J started asking money from saying he was going through financial trouble, he had become a good friend and since I was making significantly higher than him (which he knew) so I gave him the money he was asking. That's when it started, first it were small amounts then it gradually increased, I too kept giving because he returned the amount he borrowed on time as soon as we got our salary. Around 4 months back I had to buy a new laptop, phone, earbuds all together since everything I owned had become 4-5 yrs old I wanted to spend and enjoy. Due to this I did not have a lot of spare cash that month and did not want break my savings so I said No to J when he asked me to loan him a significant amt (around 35% of my monthly salary) he immediately pointed out that I earn more than him and am single and have my own house while he is married, has a small child and lives on rent and I should thus help him out.//He said I am the only colleague who considers his friend and he cannot ask anyone else for the same. He failed to return the money on time the first time since he started borrowing from me, 1 more month passed theresfter too. I did not pester him, he borrowed 2 more times without paying anything back and 2 weeks ago I and a few other colleagues were having coffee break and were planning a small trip on the weekend to celebrate and relax after a hectic month. One colleague said he would not be able to come, on digging we knew he was short on cash since he loaned J some money and I felt so betrayed that I blurted out that J took a loan from me too, this opened the flood gates and it turns out J has taken loan from nearly half of the office. This word got to HR dept soon and J had a rough meeting with HR where he was told tht while the company cannot force him to pay up to us and other members who loaned to him, he would be fired if this goes on to not frthr spoil the cmpny envrnmnt.//He immediately came to me when we were leaving the office at day end and first accused me of telling others that he borrowed from me and then demanded another loan so he could pay up to colleagues whose payments were pending since quite some time so he does not lose his job.I made a pretty good incentive last moth and had a lot of spare cash in my account but I told him no and that I feel exploited by him and it is not my fault he earns less then me or cannot manage his finances better. He started crying m, told me I was inhuman and he got mouths to feed.//AITA for blurting out the he borrowed from me too and also to tell him no this time even though I had the cash to spare?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for embarrassing a lunch thief at work." op_gender="nan" target_gender="M" experience="nan" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="yes" action="verbally insulting or disrespecting" intention="seeking fairness or justice" impact="damage to reputation" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>So pretty much the title, I don't think I am the A but I've been getting some flack for it so I really want to clear this up.//So I started a new job recently I work in small studio, there are several others in the building, think open plan office with sections assigned to each studio. The person I had an altercation with doesn't work for my studio just FYI.//I eat lunch at 1ish and most people eat at 12. I came down ealry to eat at 12, I made coffee and while at the counter noticed my tuppaware in the sink, empty.//Imagine my surprise when I turned around and saw a man I didn't know sitting down at the table with my food on his plate. He had just stuck it in the microwave. Acting rashly since I was mad, I sat down next to him and said 'hey that looks good, mind if I try it?' Then before waiting for an answer I yanked the plate away from him and snatched his fork out his hand, he just blinked in shock as did the other people there as I started eating.//He then, quite loudly, asked what I thought I was doing and I replied 'huh you know this was actually much better when I first cooked it, it probably lost some flavor in the fridge.' he caught on quickly that it was it was my food and went a lil red. I then asked him where he got the gall to steal someone else's lunch and then ask them what they were doing when they took it back.//He stuttered out some nonsense about not knowing it was mine and I replied well you knew it wasn't yours right? He just mumbled something like an apology and I said that's no problem it was nice he'd warmed it up for me at least, in an admittedly b*tchy tone, and then he just got up and left and the people there just stared in silence. 2 of the silent watchers, maybe his mates idk, told me that I was rude to him and that there had been nicer ways to go about it. I told them to think how they'd feel if someone ate their food before saying they should focus on their lunch and I'll focus on mine.//Well it's been a little awkward at lunch since and I have the impression a few people are talking shite about me at work now, maybe I could've been nicer sure. I still don't think I was wrong but tell me reddit AITA</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for asking a female co-worker if they could possibly leave me alone?" op_gender="M" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="same" industry="labor" condition="no" action="ignoring or neglecting duties or people" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="Yes">
		<content>Long story short, I am not exactly comfortable around women, and I do what I can to minimize my interactions with females as much as I can. Has nothing to with capablitles or anything I just get extremely uncomfortable.//We have a new hire that has been trying to get to know people around the office better, and I happen to just excuse myself when she comes around. Thankfully I work in the field a lot so I am often alone. So it does not happen often, but when I do come to the office she keeps trying to befriend or talk to me. I am civil and polite I say hello, and can handle idle chit-chat, even if it is visibility uncomfortable for me.//She brought this up with my friend in the office and he explained the situation, and since then it seems she has made it her mission to have me open up. On Friday I asked if she could leave me alone please, that I have no intention to become her friend or open up.//She lashed out and called me a misogynistic asshole. I thought it over the weekend and it has been racking my brain. Am I really the asshole for not wanting to put myself in uncomfortable situations if I can avoid it.//If I have to take her out in the field or help explain my drafts I will push through, since it is work related. I still get uncomfortable but it is what it is. Those are situations I cannot avoid, but general interactions I do not think it is wrong of me to limit those when possible.//On the other hand, I also understand this is a me problem, I go to therapy but that only does so much. This is something rooted in trauma and I am not comfortable writing about it. She should not be punished for my own issues.//So AITA?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA for having my co worker fired?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="higher" relationship="superior" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="no" action="lying or misrepresenting information" intention="self advancement or interest" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I 19f have been working at my job as a cashier/cook at Taco Bell for 6 months now. I love my co workers and we have a very friendly and warming environment, most of my co workers express themselves and are very blunt, which is why I loved this job so much because it was much different than all of my previous jobs.//A few weeks ago, we were closing and I was asked to help one of the newer co workers close her drawer, (she had been here for 2 1/2 weeks at this time) and the money came up short, being that she was using the drawer, the responsibility would have fallen on her and our other co worker who uses the headset to take orders. (They were working directly behind each other and he would sometimes use the register also that day). Being that I just got promoted as a shift leader manager, I was asked to recount the money, and to be certain that the funds were low. I confirmed that there was money missing, and so that night I put a note asking the general manager, my boss to call me in the morning.//The next afternoon, my boss called me and we discussed the situation, I told her that the new employee had to have taken the money since she was the only one who I watched accept cash from customers at the window, although I was unsure, I couldn’t risk losing my position as it would’ve appeared to the other managers that I didn’t know what was going on under my own watch, a few days later, I was informed that she was taken off the schedule and asked to give her uniform back.//I feel terrible for not double checking, because when I went back, I saw the $25 stuck behind the coffee maker that’s never used or looked behind, so it’s clear that she dropped it, however I can’t bring myself to tell my boss since I don’t want to lose my job either.//Aita?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for being rude to a coworker?" op_gender="F" target_gender="F" experience="same" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="telling the truth" intention="avoiding conflict" impact="strained relationships" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>I'm 25F, this involves a group of 4 lady coworkers (between 23F-40f) So one of the ladies, we'll call A, just had a baby not too long ago and she was showing the other ladies, we'll call them B and C pictures on her phone. I was walking from one of the offices to the main room and they were grouped together blocking the doorway and I just said &quot;Excuse me&quot;, A turns to me and says hi and asks if I want to see pictures of her baby, I replied &quot;Not right now, thank you&quot;, all 3 of them look at me like I sneezed on them during Covid. B then asks &quot;you don't like babies?&quot; I responded, &quot;no, I just don't really have an interest in them or kids in general but congratulations A&quot; and B then says &quot;oh God you're not one of those people who's whole personality is hating kids are you?&quot; I just kind of stared at her and asked &quot;do you wanna see my new weapons and armor I just built on Skyrim?&quot; She looked so bewildered and said &quot;no, what does that have to do with anything?&quot; I responded &quot;oh, are you one of those people who's whole personality is hating video games?&quot; A and C started laughing but B looked really embarrassed and I overheard her call me a bitch as I was walking away. AITA?//Edit: I am asking for judgement on my comment to B, NOT on the fact I didn't look at A's baby pictures. A didn't care, she just shrugged. B is who I am asking judgement for. It may come as a shock to some, but I have said no thank you to baby pictures several times and nobody gave me grief before. Just said &quot;alright&quot; and we moved on, so I felt comfortable saying &quot;no thank you&quot; here.</content>
	</item>
	<item label="YTA" title="AITA if I submit a work visa complaint against coworker/employer" op_gender="nan" target_gender="M" experience="lower" relationship="same" industry="professional" condition="no" action="disciplinary/professional action" intention="personal vendetta" impact="career consequences" good_standing="nan" perspective="No">
		<content>My coworker (29M) is in the US on an H1B work visa; he started right after he graduated college. At his first visa renewal, the company promoted him to a senior position he lacked experience to qualify for. The company did this because it was easier to justify hiring a foreign worker for the senior position than the entry level position he actually had. In this role, he was paid more than US workers with 5+ years more experience.//He was just promoted again. The job he was promoted to was posted on Indeed, Monster, etc for outside candidates. He did not meet many of the qualifications of that posting, which required 10+ years of management experience. However, the actual job he has is NOT the job description that was posted; his actual position has less requirements. It requires no previous management experience. This reduced position was never posted for other candidates to apply to. The applicant pool would be much larger because it’s an entry level manager vs the experienced. In this role, he is making $15k+ more than people in the same position but with 10-20 years of experience.//Throughout his time at my company, he’s been a condescending arsehole to me; to the point where I e had 3 coworkers tell me that he’s intentionally undermining me to leadership. 2 of the 3 have said they think it’s because I’m a woman and in his “culture“ women are below men.//Would I be TA if I submitted a complaint through immigration as these are violations of the H1B visa process?</content>
	</item>
	<item label="NTA" title="AITA for “not giving it my all” at work?" op_gender="nan" target_gender="F" experience="lower" relationship="inferior" industry="customer-facing or retail" condition="no" action="making or declining requests" intention="asserting boundaries" impact="productivity decrease" good_standing="Yes" perspective="No">
		<content>Some background info: I’ve been working at a small retail business for about 3 years. Owner is great, i hear from her often, pays me well and is just generally really good to me.//We have 2 locations, about 4 hour apart. I was the manager at location A, but decided to switch universities and move, which just so happened to be where location B was, so my boss transferred me there.//I was manager at location A, and I absolutely loved my job. Me and my employees were all friends outside of work, the owner was very happy with how I did my job, and I was always excited to come into work.//When I transferred to location B, the owner let me keep my pay, but I was going to just be a regular employee, which i was fine with.//However, I quickly realized that location B was very different from location A.//The girls there were nice at first, and for the most part are still amicable towards me. However, overtime it became obvious that they don’t like me. Everyone there is friends outside of work, and i’ve just been a little ostracized. I don’t mind much though, because they have very different interests and personalities than me. Sometimes they just make me feel a little unwelcomed.//My big issues, however, is my new manager. She is A LOT older than everyone else. The average age of people in the company, including the owner, is about 25. Manager is 65.//That being said, she has a lot of older ideas, and often uses her age as an excuse as to why she needs more days off than everyone else. She only works 20 hours a week.//From day 1, before even getting to know me, she has singled me out. “Oh we do things differently at this location, so keep up.” “Oh i use to work for a big corporation, so I know what I expect out of you.”//She is constantly texting me when I am not at work. Like, daily, asking me to come in early or stay late, changing the schedule around literally the night (9pm or later) before my shift.//She also, for whatever reason, refuses to approve my days off, but approves everyone elses.//A few months back, she gave me some days off, then revoked them mid-vacation and expected me to drop everything and come back.//Since then, i have been doing the bare minimum. I am no longer coming in on any days that she asks when i am not on the schedule. if she changes the schedule the night before, I tell her it wont work for me. I do not stay late for any reason, and i no longer do work outside of my job description.//Manager and coworkers are saying that i dont “sacrifice enough” for the job, and im not “giving it my all” anymore. Its a fucking retail job selling basically trinkets and nick nacks. But maybe I am the asshole and should just quit instead of doing more or less the bare minimum?</content>
	</item>
</dataset>
